（A24影业）
（纽约中央影业）
（九码半）
（八码半）
- 玛丽安太太 - 是九码半的吗？
- Mrs. Mariann. - You have the nine and a half?
- 是的 可给你找到了 - 太好了
- Yeah, you're a lucky lady. - Oh, I'm excited.
最后一双了 来 露个玉足吧
Last pair. Let me see those beautiful feet.
纽约
右脚还可以吧？
The right foot's all right?
来 用力伸进去
There you go. Get it in there.
- 太小了 - 加油 加油
- They're too tight. - It's okay. All right.
- 这真是九码半？ - 对 九码半
- Are these the nine and a half? - These are the nine and a half, yeah.
- 有大一号的吗？ - 唯独这牌子没有
- Do you have the next size? - No, not in a Kerrybrooke.
所以我不推荐凯步轩
But that's why I don't like Kerrybrooke,
穿他们鞋 跟裹小脚一样
because they fit really small. They're made for dolls or something.
- 太不合脚了 - 好吧 脱下来吧 脱下来吧
- They're too tight. - Okay, take 'em off. Don't worry about it.
- 穿过足力康吗？ - 没有
- You ever try Vitality? - No.
- 这牌子档次更高 更耐穿 - 稍等一下
- It's a much better model if you want durable leather. - I'll be right with you.
- 打扰了 - 拿来试试吧
- Excuse me. Sorry. - I'll try it.
我要找前几天卖我鞋的 戴眼镜的那位
I bought a pair of shoes here the other day from him, with the glasses.
- 马蒂 - 怎么了？
- Marty. - Yeah?
有位顾客找你 前几天是你卖她鞋吗？
This woman said she bought a pair of shoes from you.
哦 对 是买了那双棕色玛丽珍吧
Oh, yeah. You bought the brown Mary Janes, right?
- 没错 鞋挺好的 - 合脚吗？
- Yeah, I did. They're great. - How do they fit you?
- 我当时穿着就走了 - 好
- I wore them out of the store. - Okay.
- 然后旧鞋就落在这里了 - 旧鞋长什么样？
- So I left my old ones here. - Okay. What did they look like?
拼色高跟鞋 带小翅膀图案
They're two-toned pumps, wingtips.
- 洛伊 有见到那鞋吗？ - 没有
- Lloyd, did you see her shoes? - No.
不会被你们装回我没拿走的鞋盒
Is it possible that you maybe put them in one of the boxes of the other shoes
然后又塞回库房了吧？
that I was trying on and restocked them?
- 好吧... - 要是看见鞋盒 我就能认出来
- Okay. All right. Um... - If I saw the boxes, I'd be able to recognize it.
让我同事来帮您选购好吗？
Do you mind if my colleague helps you out for a second?
洛伊 你帮忙接待一下这位行吗？
Lloyd. Can you help with Mariann here?
没问题 等下
Sure. Sure.
- 走 跟我去仓库 - 谢谢 借过
- Yeah, we'll check the basement. Come. - Thank you. Excuse me.
- 洛伊会拿来足力康的 - 好吧 我得考虑下价格
- Lloyd's gonna help you. Get the Vitalities. - Okay. I'll think about the price.
- 您先坐会儿 我马上就来 - 好的 谢谢
- I'll be right with you. Let me finish up here. - Okay, thank you.
- 怎么了？ - 嘘
- What? - Shh.
- 是马蒂吧? - 是 真倒霉
- Marty. - Ah, fuck.
给你看个东西 进来一下
I wanna show you something. Come here.
- 什么？ - 蹲下 赶紧蹲下
- What? - Just get low. Go low.
我干嘛非得蹲着啊?
Why do I have to get low?
- 舅 一切还好吧 - 马蒂 瞧瞧我给你准备的
- How you doing? - Marty, look what I got for ya.
什么东西？
What is this?
仔细瞧瞧
Check it out.
（诺金鞋行 家用鞋履 经久耐穿）
有啥特别的？
What am I looking at?
看看背面
Turn it over.
（马蒂·毛瑟 管事）
- 做管事? - 对 管事
- Manager? - Manager.
得了吧 老默
Come on, Murray.
答不答应 千万别跟洛伊提这事儿啊
Whatever you do, just don't tell Lloyd about this.
舅 我不是不尊重你 但把话讲明白
Look, I've been very clear with you. I'm not...
这店子你经营得确实不错
trying to be disrespectful. You built something very commendable here.
现在别 别谈这些
I don't wanna-- I don't wanna discuss this now.
别打断我 让我说完
Stop. Stop. Let me say something.
这活确实让我学到不少
It's been good for my soul to see this up close and personal.
- 但我不是来卖鞋的 - 我不想听这些
- But I'm not a shoe salesman. - I don't wanna discuss this.
- 我不是这块料 - 别扯这些 行吗？
- I'm not a shoe salesman. - I don't wanna discuss this, okay?
必须谈 等我飞走 我就不干了
I do wanna discuss it, 'cause when I'm back from my trip, this is over.
我不可能留在这行
I'm not coming back and doing this.
说到这 工钱现在能结吗 我得去买机票
Speaking of which, can we settle up now? I gotta buy my plane ticket.
打烊再结
We'll settle at closing.
我得趁午休去买票
I wanted to see the travel agent on my lunch break.
你拿到钱肯定不回来了
You'll never come back after your lunch break.
你真把我看成那种人？
That's what you think of me?
- 对 - 你真以为我会跑了不回来吗？
- Yes. - You think I would go and not come back?
对 我说了打烊再结 行吗？
Yes. I said settle at closing, okay?
- 就这样？ - 对 就这样 出去吧
- That's it? - Yeah, that's it. Goodbye.
真是我的好舅舅
I love you.
- 快点 - 等我一下
- Come on. - Wait. Just wait for me.
- 我本来就...正要去你家的 - 啥？
- I was about... I was about to come to you. - What?
不行 艾勒在家病着呢
No, Ira's home sick.
- 喂喂喂 什么病 别传染给我 - 什么？
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. I can't get sick. - What?
我得去打锦标赛 我可不能病
I got the championships.
不是 他是吃坏肚子了 只是吃坏肚子了
No, it's food poisoning. It's food poisoning.
真想把你塞进行李箱带走
I wish I could hide you in my luggage.
我也好想跟你走
I wanna come with you so bad.
♪ 趁还有机会 跳起来吧 ♪
♪ Let's dance in style, let's dance for a while ♪
♪ 别靠天命 活在当下吧 ♪
♪ Heaven can wait, we're only watching the skies ♪
♪ 盼着好事 也做好最坏打算 ♪
♪ Hoping for the best but expecting the worst ♪
♪ 明天会不会就烟消云散？ ♪
♪ Are you gonna drop the bomb or not? ♪
♪ 要么痛快地死 要么好好活下去 ♪
♪ Let us die young or let us live forever ♪
主演
提莫西·查拉梅
♪ 命靠天定 但我们偏要逆流而上 ♪
♪ We don't have the power but we never say never ♪
♪ 潮来潮去 人生苦短啊 ♪
♪ Sitting in a sandpit, life is a short trip ♪
主演
格温妮斯·帕特洛
♪ 能懂这歌的人 也懂我的伤 ♪
♪ The music's for the sad men ♪
主演
敖德萨·阿锡安
♪ 这场竞赛会怎么收场？ ♪
♪ Can you imagine when this race is won? ♪
♪ 是胜利还是灭亡？ ♪
♪ Turn our golden faces into the sun ♪
主演
凯文·奥利里
♪ 我们唱着赞歌 别无选择 ♪
♪ Praising our leaders, we're getting in tune ♪
♪ 魔鬼弹着舞曲 逼我们起舞 ♪
♪ The music's played by the, the mad man ♪
主演
泰勒·奥康马
♪ 永远年轻 ♪
♪ Forever young ♪
原创译制
蒙太奇字幕组
♪ 我想永远年轻 ♪
♪ I want to be forever young ♪
♪ 谁不想永远活着？ ♪
♪ Do you really want to live forever? ♪
♪ 永远永远地活着 ♪
♪ Forever and ever ♪
（至尊马蒂 美国制造）
♪ 永远年轻 ♪
♪ Forever young ♪
♪ 我想永远年轻 ♪
♪ I want to be forever young ♪
♪ 谁不想永远活着？ ♪
♪ Do you really want to live forever? ♪
反手 反手 反手
Backhand. Backhand. Backhand.
正手 正手 正手
Forehand. Forehand. Forehand.
演出
法兰·德瑞雪
反手 反手 反手
Backhand. Backhand. Backhand.
演出
阿贝尔·费拉拉
正手 正手
Forehand. Forehand.
反手 反手
Backhand. Backhand.
演出
艾莫里·科恩
放高球
And lob.
正手
Forehand.
演出
盖札·罗里格
- 马蒂 - 干嘛
- Marty! - What!
- 有电话 - 跟他说我二十分钟前就走了
- Phone! - Tell him I left 20 minutes ago!
我才不当你的传声筒 自己去接那该死的电话
I'm not your goddamn messenger! Pick up the goddamn phone!
演出
佩恩·吉列特
我跟不上 沃利 把白衬衫脱了
I can't. Wally, take the white shirt off.
白球配白衬衫 看不清
I can't follow the white ball against the white shirt.
别找借口 孬种才这样找借口
Stop it. You're a fucking sun dodger.
演出
桑德拉·伯恩哈德
我孬种？怎么怕了 怕了？
Oh, yeah? I love you. I love you.
喂
Hello?
我是朱迪
It's Judy.
演出
川口功人
怎么了 朱迪
Hi, Judy.
你妈病得很重
Your mother, she's very sick.
- 真的假的？ - 真的
- Okay, really? - Yes.
她脸色苍白 满嘴胡话
She's gray in the face. She's speaking nonsense.
演出
拉瑞·拉索·斯洛曼
她一直喊你 你得赶快回家一趟
She's asking for you. You should come home.
听上去不行了 你们赶紧叫救护车吧
Sounds really bad. You should probably call an ambulance.
演出
卢克·曼利
谁陪她去啊
Who's gonna go with her?
我不知道 你这么上心 你陪她去呗
Uh, I don't know. You should probably go since you're so invested.
等一下 别挂
Hold on a minute.
他不吃这套
He's not buying it.
跟他说我断气了
Just tell him I stopped breathing!
（至尊马蒂 美国制造）
绝对不行 太严重了 我不能这么说
Absolutely not. That's ridiculous. I'm not saying that.
跟他说你正急着送我去医院
Tell him you're taking me to the hospital.
好吧 我得赶紧把她送去急诊
Okay, fine. I'll take her to the emergency room
然后在那儿陪着 天知道要陪多久
and sit there and wait for God knows how long.
“你来负责伺候我丈夫 给他喂药”
And you can come here and give my husband his medicine
“晚上给他翻身做按摩”
and massage his feet all night long.
“跟他说我晕倒了”
Tell him I passed out.
配乐
丹尼尔·洛帕汀
- “天呐 你妈刚刚昏过去了” - 你好啊 小姑娘
- Oh, my God! Your mother, she just lost consciousness. - Hi, sweetheart.
“你现在赶紧回家”
You've gotta come home now.
谁啊
Hello?
是我 饭马上好
Hi. Just give me a second.
“朱迪 别闹了行吗”
I don't know what you want me to say, Judy.
“我正忙着 连午饭都还没吃呢”
I'm busy. I'm on my lunch break.
“我妈就在你旁边指挥 我都听得见”
I can hear her whispering. She's right there standing next to you.
- “我都说她昏过去了”- “别来烦我了”
- I told you she passed out.- It's annoying me now.
跟谁通话呢？
Who are you talking to?
哦 没人
Oh. I'm not talking to anybody.
朱迪一直占着电话好久了
Judy's just been tying up the line for an hour.
我给你买了点热饭
I got you some broth.
剪辑
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
都凉透了
It's ice cold.
- 买饭排了好久 买回来都凉了 - 你都不打草稿？
- Yeah, 'cause the line was really long at the shop. - Oh, yeah?
信不信我现在打电话去核实？
So that's what they'll say if I call down and ask?
你要是觉得我骗你
You don't believe me? You calling me a liar?
你就打电话核实去
Pick up the phone and call them.
- 不过看你怎么打 朱迪在占着电话 - 喔 行
- You're gonna have to get Judy off the phone first. - Oh, okay.
喂 朱迪 把电话给我挂掉
Hey, Judy, get off the phone.
摄影
达吕斯·康第
看 这颗是国际乒联标准球
Okay, this is a normal IATT approved ball.
【国际乒乓球联合会：1926年成立 主管国际乒乓球赛事和规则】
盯紧这颗白球
Try to follow the white ball against the white.
在白背景下挺难的吧
Almost impossible, right?
你眼珠根本没跟上
I don't even see your eyes moving.
要是我穿白衬衫 你连球都看不到
If I'm wearing a white shirt, you can't see the ball.
换颗橙球试试 这是我自个儿想出来的
Now, imagine it with an orange ball, which no one's ever thought of.
看吧 你盯得多牢 瞧他那眼神
See? You're already following it way better. Look at his eyes.
- 看见没？ - 嗯 看见了
- See how his eyes are looking? - Yeah, I see it.
你现在盯得更紧了
You're looking more engaged now.
这就是机遇所在 目前桌上网球界
So that's what we wanna do. Right now in the world of table tennis,
【桌球：乒乓球早期在上流场合叫做"桌上网球" 简称"桌球"】
为了盯住白球都得穿黑衣
you're obliged to wear black, just so you can follow the white ball.
- 看看这个 这是泰德·贝利 - 他是谁？
- Look at this. That's Ted Bailey. - Who's that?
他曾是英国冠军 世界第一
That's ex-number one ranked player in the world right now.
已经被我打败了
He's the British champion. I've already beat him, by the way.
再看这个
Now look at this.
网球界第一杰克·克雷默
That's Jack Kramer, number one tennis player.
【杰克·克雷默：40-50年代著名网球手 推动网球精英化】
- 有啥区别？ - 他穿的是全白
- What's the difference there? - He's wearing all white.
对 一身白 很绅士
He's in all white. It's beautiful.
【50年代网球为绅士运动 桌上网球(乒乓球)尚非主流】
这叫品味 这叫格调 这是卖点
To me, that's luxury. To me, that's class. You could sell that.
马蒂 这种定制球得花不少钱
Marty, a custom ball like that is gonna cost a lot of money.
当然得定制 奇人配奇球
Of course it's custom. It's an original ball for an original guy.
这是至尊马蒂牌 不是平庸马蒂牌
It's the Marty Supreme ball, not the Marty Normal ball.
你算过成本吗？
But what's it gonna cost?
钱不重要 咱别抠门
It doesn't matter the cost. We can't cheap out on this.
花不了多少钱的 加拉尼斯先生
It's gonna be nominal, Mr. Galanis.
你不是老说先花钱才能赚钱吗
You always said we gotta spend money to make money, right?
制片人
提莫西·查拉梅
给我端杯咖啡来
Get me a cup of coffee.
没门 让你秘书去弄
No. Get your secretary to get ya a cup of coffee.
南希忙着呢 你去弄吧
Nancy's busy. Just get me a coffee.
才不 我正像大人那样谈生意
Dad, we're talking like men about business here.
- 我才不给你端咖啡 - 赶紧去给老子端咖啡去
- I'm not getting ya a cup of coffee. - Get me the damn coffee!
制片人
安东尼·卡塔格斯
马蒂 也给你来一杯？
Marty, you want a coffee?
谢谢 不用了 我不碰咖啡因
No, I'm all right. I'm not drinking caffeine.
听着
Listen.
我感谢你和我儿子的这份交情
I appreciate you're friends with my son.
但他不成器
He's limited.
三十岁还靠爹吃饭
He's 30 years old. He's still living at home.
没啥名堂
He hasn't done much.
他也不懂做生意 算不清账
And he doesn't know business. He doesn't know the costs.
恕我直言 盖拉尼斯先生 我不觉得他不成器
I don't think he's limited, Mr. Galanis, respectfully.
看看您做生意的本事
I mean, look at your business success.
那是刻在骨子里的 迪翁也有
That's in your DNA, and you passed that through to Dion.
- 只是还没显露出来 - 谁知道呢
- It just hasn't been awoken yet. - I don't know.
我要是没把握
I wouldn't be here trying to involve you in something that I
制片人
伊莱·布什
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
我也不会拉您入伙的
didn't fully in my bones believe in.
我很尊重您的钱 说来您可能不信
And I have tremendous respect for your money. I know it's hard to believe,
但这门运动在国外是火得不得了
but I'm telling you, this game, it fills stadiums overseas.
在美国火起来也只是时间问题
And it's only a matter of time before it fills stadiums in the United States too,
到时候我的广告会铺天盖地
before I'm staring at you from the cover of a Wheaties box.
我 我对这行一窍不通
I- I don't know nothing about this business.
确实不通 所以更该信我
No, you don't. That's why you gotta trust me.
下周这个时候 我就是首位赢下英国公开赛的美国人
This time next week, I'll be the first American to ever win the British Open.
编剧
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
到时候我就能一路杀到世锦赛 然后拿下世界第一
That'll slide me into the number one ranking for the World Championship.
到时候《生活》和《展望》都会报道
Life magazine's gonna cover it. Look magazine's gonna cover it.
这是板上钉钉的事 《展望》就在捧我 他们都会捧我
They have to. The editor of Look magazine, he loves me. They all love me.
到时候我就是这项运动在美国的唯一代言人
I'm uniquely positioned to be the face of the entire sport in the United States.
导演
乔什·萨弗迪
（家庭鞋履）
劳埃德!
Lloyd!
我要关门了
I'm closing up.
看得出来 我来找我叔
Yeah, I can see that. Just here to see my uncle.
他走了
He left.
走了? 什么叫走了? 今天不回来了?
He left? What do you mean he left? For the day?
他得送你妈去医院
He had to take your mother to the hospital.
真是够了 她没病
For crying out loud. She's not sick.
嘿 劳埃德 他欠我钱 咱们本来今天结账的
Hey, Lloyd, he owes me money. We were supposed to settle up today.
要是你没去吃那五小时的午饭
Well, maybe if you didn't take that five-hour lunch,
- 兴许就能见着他了 - 闭嘴吧你
- you would have spoke with him. - Oh, shut up.
听着精神不少啊? 好得挺快嘛
You're sounding a lot better, huh? That happened quick.
我死不了 托你的福!
I'll live, no thanks to you!
行了 妈 你跟默里在一起吗? 实话实说
Enough, Mom. Are you with Murray? Be honest.
没 我看他出发去旅行了 行吧?
No. I think he left for his trip. Okay?
旅行? 什么旅行?
His trip? What trip?
他带埃丝特去库彻度假村过周末了
He's taking Esther to Kutchers for the weekend.
但只要我开口 他肯定会留下
But he would have stayed if I asked him to.
你根本没病 妈 他本该给我路费买机票的
You're not sick, Mom. He was supposed to give me my money for my flight.
喔 宝贝 我对此一无所知
Well, I don't know anything about that, sweetie.
你少来! 你以为我为什么要在这儿打工?
Yes, you do! Why do you think I'm working here?
我接这活儿纯粹就是为了这个
I literally only accepted this job for that.
我完全听不懂你在暗示什么
I have no idea what you are implying.
- 你知道这是什么吗? - 什么 这是什么?
- You know what this is? - What, what is this?
这是蓄意破坏 你在整我
This is sabotage. You're sabotaging me.
得了吧 是你在毁掉你自己的人生
Oh, please. You're sabotaging your own life.
- 那是什么? - 什么?
- What is that? - What?
你认真的? 觉得我要抢你?
Are you seriously thinking I'm gonna rob you?
职业反应
Just a reflex.
我要是想抢你 你早死在血泊里了
If I wanted to rob you, you'd be dead. You'd be in a pool of blood.
我是来拿西装的 你知道我为了这趟旅行专门买的吗?
I came to grab my suit. You know I bought this specifically for my trip?
还没听说打乒乓球得穿西装
Didn't know you need a suit to play ping pong.
我只想拿回默里欠我的700美元
I just want the $700 that Murray owes me.
呵 不给呢?
Yeah, or what?
- 不然我就往你腿上来一枪 - 你不敢
- Or I'm gonna shoot you in the leg. - No you're not.
你确定?
You sure about that?
你往我腿上开枪 下半辈子就在牢里过吧
You shoot me in the leg, you'll be spending the next few years in jail.
那我就往你头上开枪
I'll shoot you in the head instead.
你也没那胆子
You're not gonna do that either.
听着 劳埃德 我只要说好的那份 一分都不多要
Look, Lloyd, I just want what was promised to me, not a penny more.
等我回来 带的奖金会是这个数的十倍
I'm gonna be coming home with ten times that amount in prize money.
所以睁一只眼闭一只眼 让我拿走应得的
So just turn the other cheek, let me take what I'm owed,
等我回来 匀给你整整100美元
and I'll give you an even $100 dollars when I get back.
没兴趣
Not interested.
劳埃德 拜托了 看着我
Lloyd, come on. Look at me, please.
咱俩都清楚 你巴不得看我卷铺盖走人
We both know you'd love nothing more than to see my ass get canned.
你干这活儿比我有干劲一千倍
You're a thousand times more motivated than me to do this job,
但你瞧瞧这个 行吗?
and yet look at this, okay?
瞧瞧
Look.
默里给我的 翻过来
Murray gave that to me. Flip it over.
经理 我要当你上司了!
Manager. I'm gonna be your boss!
够不公平吧? 我想开除你就开除你
How unfair is that? I could fire you whenever I want.
我还能让你跪地上扫地
I could tell you to sweep the floor on your hands and knees.
怎么样 爽吗?
How about that, okay?
劳埃德 我现在真拿枪指着你呢
Lloyd, I'm actually pointing a gun at you right now.
我是真的威胁要开火
I'm actually threatening to use it.
这可是场如假包换的抢劫 指纹到处都是
This is a legit robbery like any other. My fingerprints are all over this thing.
这就是事实
These are facts.
所以开保险箱 拿走我应得的
So open the safe, let me take what I'm owed,
完事你打电话给默里 如实禀报
and you can call Murray, tell him exactly what happened,
炒了我 告我都行 随你便 行吗?
get me fired, press charges. Whatever you want, okay?
行
Fine.
- 给您 先生 - 谢了
- Here you go, sir. - Thank you.
♪ 我偏爱那高峰时分 ♪
♪ The time I like is the rush hour ♪
♪ 只因我沉醉那喧嚣 ♪
♪ 'Cause I like the rush ♪
♪ 人潮推搡挤动 ♪
♪ The pushing of the people ♪
♪ 一切深得我心 ♪
♪ I like it all so much ♪
♪ 万物熙攘忙碌 ♪
♪ Such a mass of motion ♪
♪ 莫问去向何方 ♪
♪ Do not know where it goes ♪
咱们没有单间吗?
We don't get our own rooms?
这儿冷得要死
It's freezing in here.
现在给我严肃点 盯着我
I really need you to be serious now. Eyes on me.
巴基斯坦 看着我
Pakistan, I need you to look at me.
等等 日本今年派队来了? 瞧见没?
Wait, Japan brought a team this year? You see that?
是啊 日本人派了一队
Yeah. The Japs sent a team.
禁令解除了?
What about the travel ban?
- 肯定解禁了 - 不再禁了?
- They must have lifted it. - No more travel ban?
好了 先生们 亮下球拍吧
Okay, gentlemen, I want you to flip your paddles for me now.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
来了 一 二 三
Here we go. One. Two. Three.
别动
Hold it still.
♪ 握个手吧 ♪
♪ Shake hands ♪
赛点 毛瑟
Match point, Mauser.
获胜 毛瑟
Match, Mauser.
你让我打太多正手了 应该逼我打反手的
You let me get to my forehand too much. Should've tried to put me in my backhand.
得分 远藤
Point, Endo.
- 几比几了? - 19比4
- What's the score here? - Nineteen-four.
- 那个日本人? - 日本人把贝利虐惨了
- The Japanese guy? - Japanese guy's trashing Bailey.
他在用什么? 那是什么球拍?
What's he using? What's that paddle?
不知道 伙计 谁都没见过
I don't know, mate. No one knows.
没声音
It's silent.
- 跟幽灵一样! - 哇
- Like a ghost! - Wow.
得分 远藤
Point, Endo.
赛点
Match point.
- 打得好 马蒂 - 打得好
- Great game, Marty. - Great game.
比赛结束 毛瑟胜
Match, Mauser.
斯德哥尔摩锦标赛的冠军...
The winners of the tournament at Stockholm...
嘿 你就是拉姆·塞西 对吧?
Hey. You're Ram Sethi, right?
抱歉 能请你稍等一下吗?
Sorry, could you hold for a moment?
- 你不介意吧? - 没事 找我有事吗?
- You don't mind? - No. Can I help you with something?
我只是好奇 你们在城里住哪儿?
I was just curious, where are you staying while you're in town?
跟你有什么关系?
What business is it of yours?
我只是问问 你们住哪家酒店?
I'm just saying, what hotel are you staying at?
国际乒联的所有代表都住在丽兹酒店
All the IATT representatives are stationed at the Ritz.
- 丽兹酒店? 嗯 我也听说了 - 是的
- At the Ritz? Yeah, that's what I heard. - Yes.
- 你觉得这合适吗? - 我不懂你在暗示什么
- Do you think that's okay? - I don't know what you're implying.
- 你见过他们给我安排的地儿吗? - 有问题吗?
- Have you seen where they put me? - Is it a problem?
恕我直言 先生 那地方就是个垃圾场
Well, with all due respect, sir, it's a dump.
真抱歉 那儿没达到您的高标准
I'm so sorry it doesn't meet your high standards.
我们为所有球员提供免费住宿 毛瑟先生
We offer complimentary housing to all our players, Mr. Mauser.
据我所知 只有你在抱怨
So far as I know, you're the only one to complain.
你跟我说话的口气 就像我是街边随处可见的球员一样?
You're talking to me like I'm any player off the street, okay?
我得休息好 才能赢下锦标赛
I need good rest so I can win the tournament.
你很清楚 美国人夺冠对这项运动意味着什么
You know perfectly well what an American win will do for the future of the sport.
- 我对乒乓球有好处 塞西先生 - 那就向美乒协反映吧
- I'm good for table tennis, Mr. Sethi. - Appeal to the USTTA.
美乒协根本不存在 就在哪弄了张桌子坐了俩人
There is no USTTA. The USTTA is two guys and a desk. It doesn't exist.
- 那不是我的问题 - 这就是你的问题
- Well, that's not my problem. - It is your problem.
我要住你住的那儿! 那才是我需要的!
I wanna stay where you're staying! That's what I need!
我觉得这次谈话非常无礼
I am finding this whole exchange really offensive.
- 你感到冒犯了? - 我感到被冒犯了
- You're offended? - I am offended.
我还被冒犯了呢! 你让你们的明星球员蜷在耗子洞里!
I'm offended! You're making your star player huddle in a rat's ass!
真抱歉 刚才被打断了
I'm so sorry for that interruption.
嗯 回到锡兰和墨西哥的话题...
Um, back to Ceylon and Mexico...
- 这酒店真不赖 肯定得花不少钱 - 是啊 特别棒
- This is a nice hotel. Must cost a mint. - Yeah, very nice.
住宿费是国际乒联报销吗?
The IATT covers accommodations?
- 只给明星球员报销 - 真的吗? 这种球员有几个?
- Only for their star players. - Is that right? How many are there?
明星球员? 我不知道 反正我也没见着别人 所以就我一个
Star players? I don't know. I haven't seen any others, so one.
进半决赛了 紧张吗?
Any nerves, going into the semis?
紧张? 对阵克莱茨基? 开什么玩笑?
Nerves? Against Kletzki? No. You kidding me?
他可是过去三年的锦标赛冠军
Well, he's won the tournament for the last three years.
- 他名气可不小 - 我的名气也不小
- He's got quite the reputation. - I have quite the reputation.
听着 奥斯威辛没办成的事 我要替它办了
Look, I'm gonna do to Kletzki what Auschwitz couldn't.
行了 我要把这活儿彻底收个尾
Okay. I'm gonna finish the job.
- 我的天呐 - 哥们 话说重了点
- Jesus Christ. - A little strong, mate.
没事 我是犹太人 我能这么说
It's all right. I'm Jewish. I can say that.
事实上 仔细想想 我就是希特勒最深的梦魇
In fact, if you think about it, I'm like Hitler's worst nightmare.
为什么这么说?
And why's that?
看看我 我还在这儿呢
Look at me. I'm here.
我办到了 我站在巅峰 我是希特勒战败后的终极产物
I did it, I'm on top. I'm the ultimate product of Hitler's defeat.
行 记下来 这段不错 记下来
Yeah, write that down. That was good. Write that down.
- 写得好 - "希特勒战败后的终极产物"
- Nice one. - "Ultimate product of Hitler's defeat."
- 我就喜欢这种自信 - 把它印在我的照片下面
- I do like that confidence. - Put that under a picture of me.
谈谈你的成长背景吧
- Tell us a bit about your background. - My background?
不说笑了... 我妈死于难产
No, but seriously... My mother died in childbirth.
我爸是个赌棍输家 我两岁时他就抛弃了我
My father was a compulsive loser who abandoned me when I was two years old.
我被困在纽约的孤儿院系统里
I got stuck in the New York City orphanage system,
在一个又一个鬼地方之间被踢来踢去
got shuttled from one hellhole to the next.
- 自然也留了案底 - 那不是凯·斯通吗?
- Naturally, got in trouble with the law. - Isn't that Kay Stone?
我不想让那些破事定义我
I don't want any of that to define me.
抱歉 借过 啥?
Excuse me. Excuse me. What?
- 凯·斯通在那儿 - 就是她
- It's Kay Stone over there. - That's her.
谁啊?
Who's that?
就那个电影女星 30年代那会儿的
Well, you know, the movie actress. Like, from the 1930s.
- 机缘巧合- 机缘巧合?
- Opportunities. - Opportunities?
- 挺好看的 - 是啊 经典电影
- That was good. - Yeah, yeah. Great movie.
- 黑匣子- 我爸当年迷死她了
- Black Box. - My dad loved her.
- 是啊 - 没错
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 她红过? - 红透半边天
- She was big? - She was huge.
昙花一现 真是她
Came and went. That's her.
- 这就是好莱坞 伙计 - 没错 是她
- That's Hollywood, mate. - Yeah. It's her.
确实是
It is indeed.
是有个带湖的名字?
Something about a lake?
- 暗影湖- 嗯 那部也不错
- Shadow Lake. - Yeah, that was good.
伙计们 你们觉得我有机会吗?
Think I have a chance, lads?
下个问题
Next question.
喂?
Hello?
- 凯? - 我是
- Kay? - Speaking.
嘿 我是马蒂·毛瑟 我在皇家套房
Hey, it's Marty Mauser. I'm in the Royal Suite.
我昨天在大厅见到你了
I saw you in the lobby yesterday.
行
Okay.
对 我们对上眼了 那会儿我正接受采访呢
Yeah, we made eye contact. I was being interviewed.
我没印象
I don't recall.
我特别崇拜你
Well, I'm a huge admirer.
好的 找我有事吗?
Okay. Can I help you with something?
也许吧 我刚才把客房服务菜单全都点了一遍
Maybe. I just ordered one of everything off the room service menu.
我一个人肯定吃不完
There's no way I'll be able to eat it all alone.
啊
Ah.
所以你想让我去你房间?
So you'd like me to come up to your room?
- 嗯 没错 - 或许我该让我丈夫替我去
- Mm-hmm. Yeah. - Perhaps I should send my husband instead.
没问题 让他上来 我下去找你
Sure. He can come up here, and I'll come down to you.
- 妙极 谢谢 再见- 等等 我还想再聊聊
- Wonderful. Thank you. Goodbye.- Wait. I wanna keep talking.
为什么?
Why is that?
因为我还没跟真正的电影明星聊过天
Because I've never talked to an actual movie star.
那你现在聊过了 希望这段经历如你所愿
Well, now you have. I hope the experience was all you thought it would be.
你知道吗 其实我也算个表演者
You know, I'm something of a performer too.
- 是吗?- 对 你不信?
- Are you?- Yeah. You don't believe me?
我...
I...
你... 怎么? 说话啊?
You... What? What?
你是表演者?
You're a performer?
没错 我就是 你跟前有每日邮报吗?
Yeah, I am a performer. You got the Daily Mailin front of you?
呃 有 确实有
Uh, I do have it, yes.
行 翻到第12页
Okay. Well, turn to page 12.
呃...
Uh...
第12页
Page 12.
行 我这看的是什么?
Okay. What am I looking at here?
- 就在中间 正中间- 呃
- Down the middle, in the center.- Uh.
这是你?
This is you?
对 "天选之子" 拍得不错吧?
Yeah, "the chosen one." It's a nice picture, right?
乒乓球?
Ping pong?
我打乒乓球 来参加全英赛的
I play table tennis. I'm here competing in the British Open.
- 你多大? - 我23
- How old are you? - I'm 23.
23岁
Twenty-three.
嗯
Yeah.
我敢说你一部我演的片子都叫不上来
I bet you can't name one film I've done.
怎么这么说?
What makes you say that?
因为在你出生前我早已息影了
Because I stopped acting before you were born.
- 真的吗? 真有意思- 嗯
- Really? That's really interesting.- Mm-hmm.
凯 你拿我的刮胡刀刮腿毛了?
Kay, did you use my razor to shave your legs?
刀片钝了 我都割伤了
It's dull. I've cut myself.
- 没拿 - 谁在说话? 你丈夫?
- No. - Who's that? Your husband?
估计是有人偷溜进来拿它劈柴了
I guess someone must've snuck in and chopped wood with it.
- 我正打电话呢 - 操
- I'm on the phone. - Holy shit.
- 跟谁打? - 黛比
- With whom? - Debbie.
- 黛比 - 黛比?
- Debbie. - Debbie?
叫她干点正事
Tell her to get a life.
- 他走了吗?- 嗯
- Is he gone?- Mm-hmm.
行
Okay.
所以 为什么不演戏了? 聊聊这个
So, why'd you stop acting? Let's talk about that.
听着 我真得走了
You know, I really have to go.
你肯定怀念片场 吧? 明天来温布利看我比赛
You must miss it, don't you? Come watch me play at Wembley tomorrow.
我... 我去不了
I... I can't.
别啊 来亲眼看我把世界第一拉下马
Come on. You can watch me dethrone the number one ranked player in the world.
我没空
I'm not available.
噢 是吗? 忙什么呢?
Oh, yeah? What you got going on?
实际上 我得陪我丈夫去参加一个大型推广活动
Actually, I have a big promotional event to attend to for my husband.
噢 这样
Oh, okay.
他推广什么?
What's he promoting?
钢笔
Pens.
- 钢笔? 你认真的?- 钢笔
- Pens? Are you serious?- Pens.
- 写字用的钢笔?- 对
- Like, writing pens?- Yes.
啥? 他是个卖笔的?
What, like, he's a pen salesman?
那你们怎么住得起这种套房?
How can you afford the suite you're in?
他是洛克威尔墨水公司的老板
He owns Rockwell Ink.
噢 行吧...
Oh. Okay. Well...
是的
Yes.
- 我知道洛克威尔墨水- 我想也是
- I know Rockwell Ink.- I'm sure you do.
行
Okay.
那是什么活动?
Well, what's the event?
他请了阿加莎·克里斯蒂在哈查兹书店签售
He's hired Agatha Christie to sign books at Hatchards.
噢
Ooh.
听着真无聊
That sounds really boring.
行
Okay.
噢 真是够了
Oh, for God's sake.
- 怎么了? - 先别挂 问你个事
- What is it? - Don't hang up. Just one question.
你房间对着马路还是院子?
Does your room face the street or the courtyard?
不知道
I don't know.
回答我就行 对着马路还是院子?
Just answer the question. Is it facing the street or the courtyard?
- 院子 - 好
- The courtyard. - Okay.
去窗户那儿 你住几层?
I need you to go to the window. What floor are you on?
应该是三层
I'm on the third floor, I believe.
三层 好 完美
Third floor. Okay, perfect.
往街对面看
Look across the street.
看见那扇开着的窗了吗? 桌上还有盘水果
You see the open window with a bowl of fruit on the table?
看见了
I do.
看好了 我会让那盘子里凭空多出一个苹果
Here's what's gonna happen. I'm gonna make an apple appear in that bowl.
如果我办到了 你就推掉你那小约会 来看我比赛
And if I do, you're gonna blow off your little rendezvous and come watch me play.
不不不 我可没答应你什么 不行
No, no, no. I'm not agreeing to anything, no.
你不用答应 反正我也要做 好了吗? 一...
You don't have to agree to anything. I'm gonna do it anyway. Okay? One...
二...
two...
三
three.
我会把票留在售票处
I'll leave a ticket for you at the box office.
得分 毛瑟
Point, Mauser.
二十比五
Twenty to five.
克莱茨基大比分零比二落后毛瑟
Kletzki trails Mauser two games to nil.
局点兼赛点 毛瑟
Game and match point, Mauser.
- 这球咱们玩点花活儿 - 好啊
- Let's have a little fun with this one. - Okay.
- 玩点花的 明白? - 收到
- Have a little fun, all right? - Gotcha.
换克莱茨基发球
Service switches to Kletzki.
得分 克莱茨基
Point, Kletzki.
打得漂亮 先生们 精彩 谢谢
Very well, gentlemen. Thank you for that. Thank you.
克莱茨基发球 六比二十
Kletzki serves 6-20.
毛瑟大比分二比零领先
Mauser leads two games to zero.
再次来到毛瑟先生的赛点
Match point again for Mr. Mauser.
还是你发球 克莱茨基
Your service again, Kletzki.
得分 毛瑟!
Point, Mauser!
毛瑟以二十一比六赢下比赛 总比分三比零
Mauser wins the game and match by 21-6. Three games to nil.
毛瑟晋级决赛 对手是日本的远藤古都
Mauser's on to the finals where he will face Koto Endo of Japan.
想吃什么随便点 别看价格 行吗?
Get whatever you want. Don't even look at the prices, okay?
你点什么?
What are you getting?
我要惠灵顿牛排和鱼子酱拼盘
I'm gonna get the Beef Wellington and the caviar tasting plate
因为这是菜单上最贵的
because they're the most expensive items on the menu.
听着 咱们再说回那个哈林篮球队的事
Listen, I would like to keep going back a little bit about the Globetrotters.
- 又提哈林篮球队? - 对
- About the Harlem Globetrotters, again? - Yes.
- 我说了没兴趣 - 为什么不?
- I told you, I'm not interested. - Why not?
因为我不想去
'Cause I don't wanna do it.
报酬非常高
It's great money.
咱们还能环游世界 你见过威尼斯吗?
And we will travel all over the world. Have you seen Venice?
我不想在人家中场休息去厕所的时候
I don't wanna be doing trick shots for a halftime show
在场上表演杂耍球
while people are going to the bathroom.
那太跌份了 行吗?
That's beneath me, okay?
- 那待遇可是皇室级别的 - 服务员在哪儿呢?
- They're treated like royalty. - Where's the waiter?
- 听着 我认识干过这行的人 - 打扰下
- Listen, I know people who have done this. - Excuse me.
借过
Excuse me.
这是个绝佳的机会 我们不该错过
It's a great opportunity. We should not miss it.
马蒂
Marty.
是的 先生 有什么能帮您的?
Yes, sir. May I help you, sir?
嘿 我们可以点菜了吗?
Hi. Can we order?
当然 先生 我这就叫服务员过来
Of course, sir. Let me fetch your waiter.
- 等会 - 请说
- Hang on. - Yes.
呃 今晚洛克威尔先生那桌我买单
Uh, I'll be taking care of the Rockwell tab tonight.
记我账上 皇家套房 马蒂·毛瑟
Put it on my room. The Royal Suite. Marty Mauser.
- 记清楚 告诉他们是我买的单 - 明白 交给我吧 先生
- And make sure they know it's me, too. - I will. Leave it to me, sir.
- 别让他们拒绝 - 没问题
- Don't take no for an answer. - I won't.
- 马蒂·毛瑟 皇家套房 去告诉他们 - 好的 先生
- Marty Mauser. Royal Suite. Go tell 'em. - Will do, sir.
行了 看着我 别往那儿瞅 看着我
Okay. Look at me. Don't look there. Look at me.
- 洛克威尔是谁? - 一个蠢货
- Who's Rockwell? - Some bozo.
现在看过去 自然点 他在干嘛?
Look over now. Be subtle about it. What's he doing?
先生 他以前没来过这儿
He hasn't been here before, sir.
他在看咱们
He's looking at us.
- 真的? - 真的
- Really? - Yeah.
行 继续跟我聊 自然点
Okay, keep talking to me. Be normal.
我希望你再考虑考虑
I want you to reconsider.
咱们会是绝佳搭档 我想跟你一块儿干
We would be a great team. I wanna do this with you.
你干嘛非盯着哈林篮球队不放?
Why are you so fixed on the Harlem Globetrotters?
他们干的事挺可悲的 明白吗?
It's very sad what they do, okay?
地球上顶尖的运动员 沦落到去演马戏小丑
Some of the premier athletes on the planet reduced to acting like circus clowns.
他现在干嘛呢?
What's he doing now?
其实 他正朝咱们走过来
Actually, he's coming towards us.
- 自然点 随意些 - 行 好的 明白
- Just be normal. Act casual. - Okay, fine. Okay.
抱歉 我认得你吗?
Excuse me. Do I know you?
没
Mm-mmm.
我看并不认得
I don't think so.
那你想帮我们整桌买单?
And you wanna buy dinner for my entire table tonight?
- 是的 没意见吧? - 为什么?
- Yeah. Is it okay? - Why?
什么叫为什么? 我还需要理由?
What do you mean, why? Do I need a reason?
我换个问法 你想要什么?
Let me rephrase that. What do you want?
不 我什么都不要 这只是我表达谢意的一点小法子
No, I don't want anything. It's just my small way of saying thank you.
- 谢我? - 对
- Thank you? - Yeah.
具体谢我什么呢?
Thank me for what, specifically?
谢您的那些产品
For all your products.
我是说 要是没有钢笔 我们该怎么办?
I mean, where would we be without pens?
听着 我才艺不少 但我最自豪的一点
You know, I have many talents, but the one I'm most proud of
就是能闻出几里外的屁话--
is the ability to smell bullshit from a mile away--
我可是十足真诚的
I'm being completely sincere.
- 你哪儿人? - 纽约的 你呢?
- Where are you from? - New York. What about you?
也是纽约 你干哪行的?
New York too. What do you do?
我是个职业运动员
I'm a professional athlete.
- 真的? 什么项目? - 乒乓球
- Really? What sport? - Table tennis.
乒乓球? 那也算运动?
Table tennis? That's a sport?
当然是了 我是来参加全英赛的
Of course it is. I'm here competing in the British Open.
我明天要在温布利打决赛
I'm playing at Wembley tomorrow
观众满座 对手是日本
in front of a sold-out crowd in the finals against Japan.
我代表美国出战
I'm here representing the United States.
等等 慢着 日本? 日本也派队来了?
Wait, wait, wait. Japan? Japan has a team here?
- 我刚就这么说的 - 他们是怎么避开旅行禁令的?
- That's what I just said. - How'd they get around the travel ban?
因为乒乓球是亚洲增长最快的运动
Because table tennis is the fastest growing sport in Asia.
在那边火得不行
It's huge over there.
噢 这个你肯定感兴趣
Oh, you're gonna like this.
你知道他们管那种握法叫什么吗? 就拿球拍的姿势?
Do you know what they call their grip? The way they hold their rackets?
- 不知道 - 他们管那叫直拍
- No. - They call it penholder.
那又怎样?
So what?
你可以用这招啊
You can use that.
拿来干嘛?
Use it for what?
搞广告之类的 我哪知道 你才是生意人
For an advertisement or something. I don't know, you're the business guy.
我失礼了 这位是我的搭档 克莱茨基
I'm being rude. This is my associate, Béla Kletzki.
幸会 先生
Nice to meet you, sir.
我猜你也是乒乓球手?
I assume you're a table tennis player also?
没错 没错 其实我是35到39年的世界冠军
I am. I am. Actually, I was the World Champion from '35 to '39.
他曾是世界冠军 我今天赢了他
He was the World Champion. I beat him today.
他赢了我 但他比我年轻得多
He beat me. But he's much younger than me.
我比他强得多 更有天赋
I'm much better than him, much more talented.
我不禁注意到这个纹身 你进过集中营 没错吧?
I can't help but notice this tattoo. You were in one of the camps, weren't you?
奥斯威辛-比克瑙 没错 怎么问这个?
Auschwitz-Birkenau. Yeah. Why do you ask?
我儿子为了解放你们丢了命
My son lost his life liberating you.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
我还以为你们是被苏联人解放的
I thought you were liberated by the Soviets.
- 确实是 - 并不是美国人
- We were. - It wasn't the Americans.
我不是按字面意思说的 他在南太平洋服役
I didn't mean it literally. He was serving in the South Pacific.
那他怎么了?
Well, what happened to him?
什么意思? 他牺牲了
What do you mean? He was killed.
你觉得这很好笑?
You find that funny?
噢 天呐 不是 我有时一紧张就会发笑
Oh, God. No, I just get nervous laughter sometimes.
如果这算慰藉的话
If it's any consolation,
我明天会往他们头上投第三颗原子弹
I'll be dropping a third atom bomb on their heads tomorrow.
是啊 我敢说他老妈肯定深感慰藉
Yeah, I'm sure his mother's gonna get a lot of comfort
因为你打乒乓球纪念他呢
that you're playing ping pong in his honor.
没多大事 但我心领了
It's not that big of a deal, but I appreciate it.
告诉他-- 他以前替纳粹拆炸弹
Tell him-- He used to diffuse bombs for the Nazis.
告诉他你跟我讲过的那个故事--
Tell him the story you told me about--
我还有一桌子客人在等呢
I've got a whole table of people waiting.
等等 慢着 你肯定会喜欢这故事 告诉他
Wait, wait. You're gonna love this story. Tell him.
- 你想听吗? - 并不想 但说吧
- You wanna hear it? - Not really, but go ahead.
不 告诉他 特别精彩
No, tell him. It's beautiful.
行 我长话短说 那就是...
Okay, I'll make it quick. So...
我刚进集中营的时候 被分到了住处
when I first got to the camp, I was put into housing.
走运的是 有个军官认出了我
Lucky for me, there was an officer who recognized me.
他在1935年布拉格世锦赛上见过我
He had seen me in 1935 at the World Championships in Prague.
那家伙是个真球迷 懂吗? 铁杆粉
This guy was a real fan. I mean, a real fan, okay?
你是说他让你活命是因为你会打乒乓?
You're telling me he let you live because you played ping pong?
他们尊重我的球技 没错
They respected my skills, yeah.
后来 他们教我如何拆解SC炸弹
So then, they taught me how to dismantle SC bombs.
行吗?
Okay?
每天早上 他们都派我带着炸弹进树林
Each morning, they would send me into the woods with the bombs
就在集中营外围 在那儿就算炸了也只能伤到我自己
on the outskirts of the camp where I could only do damage to myself.
有一回
So one time,
我跟着一只蜜蜂
I followed a honeybee.
蜜蜂?
A bee?
一只蜜蜂
A honeybee,
一直跟到它的蜂巢
all the way to its hive.
我用烟把蜜蜂全都熏走了
And I smoked all the bees out.
然后把巢砸开
And then broke it open,
我把蜂蜜抹在胸口 胳膊 全身上下都是
and I smeared the honey all over my chest, my arms, everywhere.
为什么?
Why?
因为在那天深夜
'Cause later that night,
我让铺友们把蜂蜜从我身上舔掉 补充营养
I let all my bunk mates to lick the honey off of me for nourishment.
正面
Heads.
- 操 - 远藤 选什么?
- Fuck. - Endo, choice?
发球
Serve.
我去那头
I'll go to that side.
- 右手边... - 加油 马蒂! 上啊!
- On my right... - Come on, Marty! Come on!
...来自美国的马蒂·毛瑟 世界排名第二
...Marty Mauser of the United States, ranked second,
对阵来自日本的远藤古都 无排名
versus Koto Endo of Japan, unranked.
比赛采取五局三胜制
The gentlemen will battle to the best of five
每局21分
in games to 21 points.
每局须赢至少两分
Each game shall be won by at least two points.
祝二位好运
Good luck, gentlemen.
请安静
Quiet, please.
开始!
All right!
得分 远藤 1-0
Point, Endo. One-nil.
加油 美国队!
Come on, America!
得分 远藤 2-0
Point, Endo. Two-nil.
好球 马蒂!
All right, Marty!
上啊 马蒂!
Come on, Marty!
得分 远藤 3-0
Point, Endo. Three-nil.
得分 远藤 4-0
Point, Endo. Four-nil.
加油 马蒂!
Come on, Marty!
得分 远藤 5-0
Point, Endo. Five-nil.
换毛瑟发球
Service switches to Mauser.
得分 毛瑟
Point, Mauser.
9比19发球
Nine serving 19.
得分 毛瑟 10-19
Point, Mauser. 10-19.
漂亮 马蒂!
Okay, Marty!
得分 远藤 20-10
Point, Endo. 20-10.
局点
Game point.
发球
Go! Serve.
得分 远藤 21-10
Point, Endo. 21-10.
本局远藤胜
Game, Endo.
远藤大比分二比零领先
Endo leads two games to zero.
得分 毛瑟
Point, Mauser.
18-16
Eighteen-16.
得分 毛瑟 17-18
Point, Mauser. 17-18.
上啊 马蒂! 加油!
Go, Marty! Come on!
换毛瑟发球
Service switches to Mauser.
操
Fuck.
得分 远藤 17-19
Point, Endo. 17-19.
操 妈的
Oh, fuck.
得分 远藤 17-20
Point, Endo. 17-20.
赛点
And match point.
请安静
Quiet, please.
安静 坐稳了
Quiet. Settle down.
毛瑟发球
Your service, Mauser.
上啊 马蒂!
Come on, Marty!
操
Fuck.
绝对不行! 狗屁! 不行!
No, bullshit! No!
我要立刻重赛 必须用标准硬板拍!
I want a rematch right now with a standard-league hard-bat!
没法接受!
That is unacceptable!
要是我安只机械手呢?
What if I had a mechanical arm?
在球上抹胶水行不行? 这样合规吗?
What if I put glue on the ball? Would that be kosher?
他全程都在接受场外指导! 我没法接受!
Why, he was getting coached the entire time! That is unacceptable!
我打的是真刀真枪的乒乓球! 真乒乓球!
I play real table tennis! Real table tennis!
简直荒唐
Unbelievable.
简直离谱
...来自日本的全英赛冠军...
...British Open champion from Japan...
去你妈的!
Fuck you!
...远藤古都!
...Koto Endo!
您这儿有米尔顿 洛克威尔的预约吗?
Do you have a Milton Rockwell reservation?
- 打扰下?- 麻烦查下米尔顿 洛克威尔的预约
- Excusez-moi?- Milton Rockwell reservation, please.
啊 洛克威尔?
Ah, Rockwell?
听着 马蒂 我想亲口谢你
So, listen, Marty, I wanna personally thank you
谢谢你带我接触乒乓球
for introducing me to table tennis.
我压根儿没想到 这玩意在亚洲火成这样
I had no idea what a phenomenon it was in the Asias.
- 哦 没错 我知道 - 在日本也大受欢迎!
- Oh, yeah. I know. - And how big it is in Japan!
我之前就想跟你说 场面大得很
That's what I was trying to tell you. It's huge.
所以 我打算把它加入到推广活动里
So, I'm thinking of incorporating it into some of the promotional events
今年秋天我们在那边正好有活动
we're gonna be doing over there in the fall.
怎么弄? 你有什么想法?
How so? What are you thinking?
我想搞一场表演赛
What I wanna do is stage an exhibition match
就在世锦赛期间 让你跟远藤对打
around the time of the World Championships between you and Endo.
- 嗯 - 我想你会喜欢的
- Mmm. - I think you'd like that idea.
所以我想给你开个价
So I'm gonna make you an offer.
一千美元酬劳
I'll pay you a thousand dollars.
安排你住东京的帝国饭店
I'll put you up at the Imperial Hotel in Tokyo.
如果你从纽约出发 还可以坐我的私人飞机
And if you're leaving from New York, I'll give you a seat on my private plane,
让你这辈子头一回体验把什么叫奢华
and you'll fly in luxury for the first time in your life.
行 价钱晚点再谈
Okay, we can negotiate my price later.
但这是在赛前还是赛后?
But this would be before or after the tournament?
- 开赛前一周左右 - 不行 必须是赛后
- About a week before the event. - No, it's gotta be after.
真刀真枪干之前 我不能在公众面前跟他过招
I can't face off against the guy in public before it actually counts.
我很看重戏剧张力 这种张力不能被削弱
Drama is very important to me. I can't undercut the drama.
咱们别纠结这种细节
Let's not get tied up in minutiae.
我只想确认下 你是否有兴趣参加
I just want to find out if you're interested in participating.
噢 当然 任何能展示我天赋的机会我都有兴趣
Oh, yeah. Of course. I'm interested in any opportunity to show off my talents.
你也不用担心 因为这一次我会彻底碾碎他
And you don't have to worry either, 'cause this time I'm gonna obliterate him.
主要是球拍的问题
It's really the racket that I'm playing,
但我保证 准能赢
but I can assure you, it's gonna be a victory.
行了 听着 我得让你明白这是怎么回事
Okay, listen. I need you to understand what this thing's about.
这不是正式比赛
This is not an official match.
连真球都算不上
It's not even a real game.
这纯粹是商业推广 为了讨好日本佬
This is purely promotional, to entertain the Japanese people,
好让他们多买我的笔 懂吗?
so they buy more of my pens, okay?
你上去打几局 表现出色点
You're gonna play a few games. You're gonna be great.
- 但你不能打得比远藤好 - 你想让我打假球?
- But you can't play better than Endo. - You want me to lose?
马蒂 给你看个东西
Marty, let me show you something.
日本最大的杂志
Biggest magazine in Japan.
是你让远藤成了国民英雄
You made Endo a national treasure.
- 听着-- - 给我看这个干嘛?
- Listen-- - Why are you showing me this?
你觉得看了这个我会想输? 这只会让我更想赢
Do you think this makes me wanna lose? This makes me wanna win.
有时候 输了才是赢
Sometimes, when you lose you're a winner.
- 听我解释-- - 我比远藤强一万倍
- Let me explain. Let me explain. - I'm ten trillion times better than Endo.
你懂吧? 我是输在那该死的球拍上
You understand that, right? It's the racket that beat me.
- 他就是个平庸球手 - 我一点都不在乎
- He's a mediocre player. - I couldn't care less.
我不在乎乒乓球 这是场戏
I don't care about table tennis. This is theater.
- 你担心什么? - 我的名声
- What are you worried about? - My reputation.
- 你的名声? - 没错 我的名声
- Your reputation? - Yes, my reputation.
我不想为了你把名声扫地 没门
I don't wanna throw my reputation in the trash for you. I'm not doing it.
你现在不就是在搞那种马戏团式的杂耍吗?
Aren't you playing in a vaudeville circus act right now?
什么杂耍? 把话说清楚
What do you mean, vaudeville? Finish that sentence.
- 你什么意思? - 你就是个中场余兴节目 马蒂
- What are you implying? - You're the halftime show, Marty.
那可是哈林篮球队! 地球上顶尖的运动员
Of the Harlem Globetrotters! The finest athletes on the planet.
从一月到现在 至少有八万观众看过我的表演
I've probably played in front of 80,000 people since January.
你觉得这很好笑?
That's funny to you?
不 我觉得你整个人都很滑稽
No. You're funny to me.
我滑稽? 知道我觉得什么滑稽吗?
I'm funny to you? You know what's funny to me?
你这么低三下四去讨好日本人
That you want to entertain the Japanese so badly,
而他们杀了你儿子 这才叫滑稽
and they murdered your son. That's funny to me.
听着 咱俩互戳了痛点 扯平了 行吗?
Look, you struck a nerve, I struck a nerve. Okay? Now we're even.
滚出去
Get out.
别啊 你得先把欠我的那顿饭结了
Nah, I think you owe me a meal first.
"小星星"!
"Twinkle Twinkle Little Star"!
♪ 每个人终究都要学着长大 ♪
♪ And everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
- ♪ 每个人终究都要学着长大 ♪- 漂亮 教练!
- ♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪- Yeah, Coach, yeah!
三 二 一 茄子
Three, two, one. Say cheese.
茄子!
Cheese!
♪ 因为每个人终究都要学着长大 ♪
♪ 'Cause everybody's Gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 每个人终究都要学着长大 ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
打扰下
Excuse me.
喂
Hello.
别在我房间吃喝 会招虫子
Please don't eat or drink in my room. It attracts bugs.
我进屋只是为了打扫 仅此而已
I just go in there to clean. That's it.
看来你并不欢迎我
Well, you don't seem happy to see me.
是啊 看来你也不怎么欢迎我
Yeah, and you don't seem happy to see me.
那么 你现在打算住这儿吗?
So, now are you going to be staying here?
怎么 不行吗? 别担心
What, is that not okay? Don't worry.
过几周我就挪窝 不招你烦了
I'll be out of your hair in a few weeks.
别犯傻
Don't be stupid.
- 怎么? 过几周有什么事? - 世锦赛
- Why? What's in a few weeks? - World Championship.
- 在哪儿办? - 东京
- So, where's that gonna be? - Tokyo.
日本东京?
Tokyo, Japan?
你是在问我东京是不是在日本吗?
Are you asking me if Tokyo's in Japan?
你是认真的吗?
Is that a serious question?
我看你累坏了
You look very tired to me.
是啊 我刚跑了大半个地球 能不累吗
Yeah, 'cause I just traveled halfway around the world. I'm tired.
我很忙 忙着工作 忙着搞钱
I was busy. I was working. I was making money.
趁这楼里的人都在上班
You know, while everybody is at work in the building,
正是你舒舒服服洗个热水长澡的好时候
it would be a good time for you to take a nice, long, hot shower.
- 给 - 这是什么?
- Here. - What's this?
- 我给你带了东西 - 嗯
- I got you something. - Mmm.
这是埃及金字塔上的原件
It's from an original Egyptian pyramid.
那可是我们建的
We built that.
行吧
Okay.
嘿 利维 你长高了不少啊
Hey, Levi. You got a lot taller.
- 我没有 - 怎么没有
- No, I didn't. - Yeah, you did.
- 抱歉 找我有事? - 对 跟我走
- Excuse me. Can I help you? - Yeah. Let's go.
- 走 赶紧的 - 嘿! 你干嘛?
- Come on, come on. - Hey! What are you doing?
- 跟我走 快走 - 不! 你他妈到底在干嘛?
- Let's go, let's go. Let's go. - No! What the fuck are you doing?
- 你被捕了 - 我没有!
- You're under arrest. - No, I'm not!
- 被捕了 过来 别乱动! - 凭什么逮捕我?
- Yes, you are. Come here. Stop moving! - What am I under arrest for?
- 那是我的洗漱用品! 噢! - 你被捕了
- That's my toiletries! Ow! - You're under arrest.
- 犯了什么事? - 持械抢劫 走吧
- For what? - Armed robbery. Come on.
持械抢-- 你胡说什么呢?
Armed rob-- What are you talking about?
再乱动就要伤着你自己了!
You're gonna hurt yourself if you keep moving!
- 到底怎么回事? - 走
- What is going on? - Come on.
- 默里 我妈在哪? 默里 - 我让她先出去待会儿
- Murray, where's my mother? Murray. - I asked her to leave for a bit.
你让她-- 到底他妈怎么回事? 我要被抓了! 救我!
You told her-- What the fuck is going on? I'm getting arrested! Help me!
萨尔 萨尔 我想跟他单独谈谈 麻烦了 先走吧
Sal, Sal. I wanna talk to him in private. Excuse us. Just go.
- 萨尔? 你认识这人? - 要我怎么做?
- Sal? You know this guy? - What do you want me to do?
- 先去后面待会儿 - 行
- Just go in the back for a while. - Yeah.
关上门
Close the door.
行 要是闹起来了就喊一声
All right, if it gets crazy just holler.
到底他妈怎么回事 默里? 我拿的那笔钱是你欠我的
What the fuck is going on, Murray? That money I took, you owed me.
不 不 不 不 那是你持枪抢走的钱
No, no, no, no. It was money you stole at gunpoint.
- 不 你答应过我... 抱歉 - 不 你根本没...
- No, you promised me... Excuse me. - No, you didn't...
那是我的钱 结果你拿走了--
That was my money and you took--
你答应过要把那笔钱给我的 我没... 我干嘛要编瞎话?
You promised me that money. I'm not... Why would I make this up?
- 那是去英国的路费 - 你那趟旅行怎么着了?
- It was money for my trip to England. - What happened on your trip?
什么叫怎么着了?
What do you mean, what happened on my trip?
- 你输了! - 我没输!
- You lost! - No, I didn't!
- 你就是输了! - 从哪儿听说的?
- You did! - Where did you hear that?
- 不 我是被耍了 - 你知不知道有多少次
- No, I got cheated against. - Do you know how many times
- 在大半夜里... - 行了 别扯淡了
- in the middle of the night... - No, no. Stop with that.
- 闭嘴 听我说! - 少教训我
- Shut up and listen to me! - Don't lecture me.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
你根本不知道我被吵醒过多少次去保释你
You don't know how many times I had to get woken up and bail you out.
我什么时候求你干过那事?
When did I ask you to do that?
- 我什么时候找你帮过忙? - 你确实没求过我
- When have I ever asked for your help? - You never asked me to do that.
- 就是啊! - 但我还是做了
- Exactly! - But I did.
现在 你得像个大人样了
And now, you're gonna be a big boy.
- 轮到你了 - 像个大人样?
- It's your turn. - A big boy?
- 你真跟我这么说话? - 没错 听着...
- Did you really just say that to me? - Yeah. Yeah, you know, look...
我不可能养你妈一辈子
I can't support your mother for the rest of my life.
- 你不用养 - 噢 是吗? 凭什么?
- You're not gonna have to. - Oh, yeah? Why not?
- 因为我要承担起来了 - 你承担? 怎么承担?
- Because I'm gonna step up. - You're gonna step up? How?
你没法想象 她会住在第五大道
In a way you can't imagine. She's gonna be living on Fifth Avenue
住在有电梯的高档公寓里
in an apartment and building with a elevator,
还有专门开电梯的人 随叫随到
and a man who works in the elevator that takes her every time she needs to use it.
行了 行了 听着
Sure, sure, sure. All right, look.
我给你两个选择 行吗?
I'm gonna give you two options, okay?
我想你会喜欢第一个
I think you'll like the first one.
你回店里上班
You come back to the shop.
这回 别再扯淡了
This time, no more bullshit.
别再搞这些乒乓球的荒唐事了 行吗?
None of this ping-pong mishegoss, okay?
我会给你更大的权责
I'm gonna give you much more responsibility,
因为说实话 你是个了不起的推销员
because truth be told, you're an amazing salesman.
我能把鞋卖给残疾人
I could sell shoes to an amputee.
那又怎样? 另一个选择呢?
So what? What's the other option?
我控告你
I press charges.
- 劳埃德是证人... - 你不会那么干的
- Lloyd is a witness... - You're not doing that.
...你得去蹲大牢!
...and you go to jail!
真的? 对你亲外甥这么狠? 你疯了吗?
Really? You'd do that to your own kin? Are you out of your mind?
- 走着瞧... 这是自作自受 - 嘿 萨尔! 萨尔!
- We'll see... You took it upon yourself. - Hey, Sal! Sal!
- 干嘛? - 他现在给你开多少钱?
- What? - How much is he paying you right now?
你在说什么 给我开钱?
What are you talking about, paying me?
我舅舅花多少钱雇你来吓唬我?
How much is my uncle paying for you to scare me?
不管多少 我出双倍让你给我跪下舔干净
'Cause whatever it is, I'll double it for you to suck my dick.
- 什么? - 给我舔
- What? - Suck my dick.
- 你口臭太他妈难闻了 - 嘴放干净点 你这--
- You have terrible breath. - Watch your mouth, you--
- 噢! 操! - 走 咱们现在就走
- Ow! Fuck! - Let's go. We're going now.
- 他刚才打我! - 住手 拜托停下
- He just hit me! - Stop. Please stop.
- 默里 他打我 - 停下
- Murray, he hit me. - Stop.
我们都商量好了
We worked everything out.
你在别的屋子 没听见 我们已经谈妥了
You were in the other room. You didn't hear. We already worked it out.
- 他会赔偿一切 - 畜生
- He's paying back everything. - Animal.
他把钱给我了 万事大吉
He gave me the money, and everything's okay.
- 你从哪弄来的? - 我从你行李箱里拿的
- Where did you get that? - I got it from your luggage.
你疯了吗? 那是我去日本的钱!
Are you out of your mind? That's my money for Japan!
- 你他妈疯了吗? - 走 赶紧走
- Are you out of your fucking mind? - Let's go. Let's go.
就把他带去市局 妈的! 带他走!
Just take him downtown, damn it! Take him downtown!
- 行了 好了! 我不闹了! - 你玩完了 彻底完了
- Okay. All right! Okay! I'll stop! - You're done. You're done.
- 拜托 停下 住手 - 跟我走
- Please. Stop. Stop. - Let's go.
- 行了 放他走 放开他 - 放他走?
- All right. Let him go. Let him go. - Let him go?
- 放开他 让他走 - 坐好
- Let him go. Let him go. - Sit up.
听着 道个歉
Listen, apologize.
行 抱歉 我错了
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
给他解开手铐
Take his cuffs off.
- 咱们接下来的打算 听好了? - 行
- This is what's gonna happen, okay? - Okay.
咱们去花园咖啡馆见你妈
We're gonna meet your mom at the Garden Café.
咱们好好吃顿饭
We're gonna have a really nice dinner.
之前的破事儿就翻篇了 行吗?
And let's just put all this shit behind us, okay?
行 没问题
Okay. All right.
- 我错了 我错了 真心对不住 - 你知错了?
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - You're sorry?
剩下的事儿咱们去解决 赶紧穿衣服
We'll take care of everything. Just get dressed.
- 好了 舅舅爱你 - 行 我也爱你
- Come on. I love you. - All right. I love you too.
你那外甥就是坨狗屎 你知道吧?
Your nephew's a piece of shit, you know that?
噢 天呐 实在对不住
Oh, Jesus. I'm so sorry.
这儿再给你十块
Here another ten.
行 没问题
Yeah, all right.
花园咖啡馆? 你都点什么?
Garden Café, huh? What do you get?
熏牛肉啊 还能有什么?
The pastrami, what else?
- 噢 熏牛肉 - 你点什么?
- Ah, pastrami. - What do you get?
烤牛肉
Roast beef.
- 烤牛肉? - 昂
- Roast beef? - Yeah.
外行条子!
Goyishecop!
嘿
Hey.
开门 赶紧的
Open up. Come on.
- 把它撞开 - 冲进去?
- Break it down. - Break it in?
操!
Fuck!
嘿! 你往哪跑?
Hey! Where you going?
该死
Shit.
- 出什么事了? - 他跳窗跑了
- What happened? - He went out the window.
- 什么? 等等! - 弗兰基!
- What? Wait! - Frankie!
- 什么? - 他正顺着消防梯往下爬呢
- What? - He's coming down the escape right now.
他在那儿! 顺着消防梯下去了!
There he goes! Down the escape!
- 噢 操 - 追 追 追!
- Oh, shit. - Go, go, go!
- 我去后头打个电话 - 拿稳了
- I'm just gonna use the phone in the back. - You hold it.
瞧见他有多喜欢你了吗?
See how much he likes you?
- 喂?- 嘿 沃利 怎么样? 我是马蒂
- Hello?- Hey, Wally. How you doing? It's Marty.
- 今晚出车吗? - 废话 当然出
- Are you working tonight? - Of course I'm working.
行 太棒了 带着车 尽可能多带点现金
Okay, great. Bring your cab and as much cash as you can.
到28街的海尔西找我 听明白没?
I want you to meet me at The Halsey on 28th Street, okay?
什么? 你又想去混场子了?
What? You wanna go hustling again?
没错 正是这意思
Yeah, exactly.
不不不 上回我被虐惨了
No, no, no. I got my ass kicked last time.
咱们大老远跑去斯塔滕岛
We went all the way to Staten Island,
结果十分钟不到 他们就认出你来了
and within ten minutes, they recognized you.
没事 咱们去昆提过的新泽西那地儿
It's fine. We're gonna go to that place that Quinn was talking about in Jersey.
那可不是什么好主意
That's a bad idea.
- 这是你的新宠物 - 不 妈 我想要犰狳
- That's your new pet. - No, Mom, I want the armadillo.
不 我已经--
No, I already--
知道吗? 我就给你买那只犰狳
You know what? I'm just gonna get you the armadillo.
我把它给你 然后你自己决定 行吗?
I'm gonna give him to you, and then you can make a decision. Okay?
它们不是爬行动物 是哺乳动物
They're not reptiles. They're mammals.
行 太棒了 你真是个好人 一个半小时后见
Okay, great. You're a beautiful man. I'll see you in an hour and a half.
- 哪儿?- 海尔西 就这样 爱你
- Where?- At the Halsey. Okay. I love you.
谢了 拜
Thank you. Bye.
很好 给你
Good. Here you are.
拜托 有后门或者别的小道能走吗?
Is there a way I can go out the back or something, please?
干嘛? 你干嘛这么看着我?
What? Why are you looking at me like that?
你就不打算跟我说点什么吗?
Aren't you gonna say something to me?
说什么 恭喜吗?
What, congratulations?
- 恭喜? - 对
- Congratulations? - Yes.
- 你开玩笑吗? - 你想让我说什么?
- Are you kidding me? - What do you want me to say?
我找了你整整八个月
I've been trying to get in contact with you for eight months.
我知道你想干嘛 没用的
I see what you're trying to do. It's not gonna work.
- 你说什么? - 那种不是我的
- Excuse me? - That's not mine.
- 绝对是你的 - 不可能 我都是拔出来的
- It is absolutely yours. - No, it's not. I pull out.
艾拉也拔出来吗?
Does Ira pull out?
- 你想让我怎么回? - 很简单的问题
- What do you want me to say to that? - It's a simple question.
他跟你干那事儿的时候也拔出来吗?
Does he pull out when he has sex with you?
- 回答我 - 你非要我回答这个?
- Answer it. - You want me to answer that?
对! 回答我! 他在那什么的时候...
Yes! Answer it. Does he pull out when he...
对不起 对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我现在一团糟 瑞秋 真的乱透了
I'm a mess right now. I'm really a mess, Rachel.
顺便说下 我在伦敦输了--
I lost in London, by the way--
嘿!
Hey!
天呐
God.
这是干嘛?
What's this?
他爸爸过世了
His father died.
- 扯淡! - 她是我八岁就认识的朋友
- Bullshit! - This is my friend since I was eight.
我在跟你说话吗?
Am I talking to you?
艾拉 我八岁就认识她了
Ira, I've known her since I was eight years old.
我爸刚走 她在安慰我
My father just died. She was consoling me.
亲爱的 没事
Honey, it's okay.
- 闭嘴! 别碰我! - 你就这么跟老婆说话?
- Shut up! Don't touch me! - That's how you talk to your wife?
对 我就这么跟她说话
Yeah, that's how I talk to her.
行
Okay.
别 别 别! 来啊 继续说
No, no, no! Come on. Keep going.
- 继续啊 - 马蒂 算了 别说了
- Keep going. - Marty, just stop.
我要把他脑门上那条他妈的一字眉给撕了!
I'll rip that unibrow right off his fucking forehead!
你想动手? 跟个大猩猩似的?
You wanna get physical? Like an ape?
艾拉
Ira.
艾拉! 快回来 你干嘛呢?
Ira! Come back inside. What are you doing?
谁快去他妈的把条子叫来?
Somebody get the fucking cops over here, huh?
- 你干了什么? - 操! 我得闪人了
- What did you do? - Fuck! I gotta get out of here.
你跑什么? 条子追你干嘛?
Why are you running from the cops?
快点 他就在这儿!
Come on, he's right here!
没后门能溜吗?
There's no way out the back?
- 什么? 什么-- - 拜托! 快点 瑞秋! 精神点
- What? What-- - Please! Come on. Rachel! Focus.
通往后院 走
it leads out the back. Go.
行 行 谢谢 谢谢
Okay. Okay. Thank you, thank you.
回头再跟你说 回头再说
I'll tell you later. I'll tell you later.
哥几个 见着个戴眼镜的白人小子打这儿路过吗?
Guys, you see a white kid with glasses come through here?
没人看见他?
Nobody saw him?
听不懂英语 昂?
No English, huh?
如需继续通话 请投币五分
Please insert a nickel if you'd like to continue the conversation.
五分? 电话要断了
A nickel? They're gonna cut us off.
- 你有五分吗? - 没
- Do you have a nickel? - No.
妈 我没撒谎 我保证这是最后一次
Mom, I'm not lying. I promise you this will be the last time.
我眼瞎了吗 那是他妈的"小老鼠"?
Are my eyes broke, or is that motherfucking Mouse?
- 谢了 - 怎么着 宝贝?
- Thank you. - What's up, baby?
太谢谢了 真是帮大忙了 谢谢
Thank you so much. I really appreciate it. Thank you.
马蒂 你闻着像股鱼腥味
You smell like a fish, Marty.
所以咱们得开个房 我得洗个澡
That's why we gotta get a hotel room. I need to get a shower.
嘿 哥们 弄个房间 行吗?
How you doing? Hey, can we get a hotel room, please?
- 四块钱 - 你刚还说三块呢
- Four dollars. - You said it was three dollars.
- 那是上个房间的价格 现在四块 - 怎么现在变四块了?
- That was for the last room. It's four. - Why is it four dollars now?
借我四块 我保证还你
Let me get four bucks. I'll pay you back, I promise.
我丑话说在前 咱们一共就十块本钱
I'm telling you right now, we only got ten to play with.
你就带了十块?
You brought ten dollars?
- 你才提前一小时通知我 - 那咱们怎么赢钱?
- You gave me a hour notice. - How are we supposed to make money?
我得养娃呢! 我就是个操蛋的出租车司机
I got kids! I'm a fucking taxi driver.
有便宜点的房吗? 差点儿没事
Do you have a cheaper room? It doesn't have to be nice.
五楼有一间 但不能洗澡
There's a room on the fifth floor, but you can't use the shower.
- 行 那个多少? - 两块五
- Okay, how much is that? - Two fifty.
拿三块给我 谢谢
Let me get three dollars. Thank you.
你最好还我 算你走运 我还拿你当哥们
You better pay me back. You lucky I love you.
- 吉米 吉米 - 待会从赢的钱里扣
- Jimmy. Jimmy. - It's coming out your winnings.
钥匙给我
Give me the keys.
什么味儿?
What's that smell?
噢 我的天! 操
Oh, my God! Fuck.
- 哇! 那是什么? - 噢 我的天!
- Wow! What is that? - Oh, my God!
他出了点小意外
He had a little accident.
天呐! 他拉了个大的
God! He had an enormous accident.
太恶心了
That's horrible.
- 闻着像坨屎! - 操!
- Smells like shit! - Fuck!
吉米 你臭得像坨屎
Jimmy, you smell like shit.
- 是你口臭还是那狗臭? - 能把钥匙给我了吗?
- Is that your breath or the dog? - Can I get my key, please?
别带着那狗进电梯 走楼梯
Do not go in the elevator with that dog. Take the stairs.
- 跟我开玩笑呢? - 给那狗洗洗
- Are you kidding me? - Wash that dog.
再见 吉米
Goodbye, Jimmy.
- 她肚子多大了 马蒂? - 很大 挺大的
- How big is she, Marty? - Very big. Big.
明天就生吗?
Is she popping out tomorrow?
我哪知道什么时候生 听着 我只知道孩子不是我的
I don't know when she's popping out. Look, all I know is it's not mine.
她有阴谋 你不像我这么了解她
She has an agenda. You don't know her like I do.
她困在一段操蛋的婚姻里 生活过得一塌糊涂
She's stuck in a miserable marriage. She has a horrible life.
她就是想赖在我头上
She's trying to pin it down on me.
从咱们八岁起 她就想把我套牢
Since we were eight years old, she's trying to get me stuck.
- 就为了套你这穷光蛋? - 没错
- Your bummy ass? - Yes.
也是 她确实疯
Yeah, she is crazy.
那孩子从生物学上讲 绝不可能是我的 行吗?
It's a biological impossibility that that kid is mine, okay?
- 所以 你带"雨衣"了? - 没 我不需要
- So, you using raincoats? - No, I don't need to.
那你的子弹肯定是哑的
So you must be shooting blanks.
你知道什么叫憋尿吗 沃利? 不知道?
Do you know what continence is, Wally? No?
每次我撒尿的时候 我都会憋住
Every time I take a piss, I pull back,
憋住 默数到十个数
I hold my urine in, and I count to ten Mississippi.
锻炼肌肉就得靠这个
That's how you build up the muscle.
你那是他妈的找膀胱炎呢
That's how you get a fuckin' bladder infection.
你干嘛呢? 那是我的信
What are you doing? That's my mail.
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
你得去买那些该死的尿布
You need to grab them goddamn diapers.
不去
No.
给我清醒点
And get a fucking grip.
我才不当什么爹
I'm not a father.
- 哟 马蒂 - 怎么?
- Yo, Marty. - What?
丽兹酒店是哪出?
What's the Ritz?
干嘛?
Why?
你收到一张1500美元的罚单
You got a $1,500 fine
国际乒联发来的...
from the International Table Tennis...
- 啥? - ...说是协会要...
- What? - ...Association and...
- 还要... - 拿进来给我!
- And they... - Bring it in here!
- 还要把你这弱鸡给禁赛了 - 拿给我
- And they banned your scrawny ass. - Give me that.
这他妈怎么回事?
What the fuck?
- 你没事吧? - 你他妈又是谁?
- Are you okay? - Who the fuck are you?
天呐! 救命! 把这鬼玩意儿从我身上挪开!
God! Help me! Get this fucking thing off of me!
我的狗!
My dog!
- 操! - 见鬼! 发生什么了?
- Holy shit! - Shit! What happened?
快点! 从那破浴缸里滚出来帮帮我!
Come on! Get outta that fuckin' tub and help me!
我的狗快淹死了 伙计 快啊! 帮帮我!
My dog's drowning, man. Come on! Help me!
行 我把它翻过来 把手抽出来
Okay, I'm flipping it. Take your arm out.
- 一 二 - 把它抬开!
- One. Two. - Lift it off!
三
Three.
快把手抽出来! 噢我的天! 我的天!
Take your arm out! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
操! 操!
Fuck! Fuck!
噢 妈的 你的手
Oh, fuck, your arm.
往后靠 往后靠 别看伤口
Lean back. Lean back. Don't look at it.
- 我得弄个止血带 - 噢 操!
- I need to make a tourniquet. - Oh, fuck!
- 过来 手给我 - 你要干嘛?
- Come here. Give me your arm. - What are you doing?
- 你干什么? - 手给我
- What are you doing? - Give me your arm.
- 妈的 - 我的狗呢?
- Fuck. - Where's my dog?
别管那狗了! 手给我
Don't worry about the dog! Give me your arm.
- 摩西 - 别乱动 别乱动
- Moses. - Do nothing. Do nothing.
有我在呢 别担心
I got you. Don't worry.
沃利 快叫救护车!
Wally, call an ambulance!
- 你还好吧? - 不 我一点也不好
- Are you good? - No, I'm not good.
我的眼镜呢?
Where are my glasses?
我是问你伤着没? 你刚把地板砸穿了
I mean, are you hurt? You just fell through the floor.
真他妈扯淡 我得把钱要回来
Fucking horseshit. I'm getting our money back.
把钱要回来?
Getting our money back?
马蒂 咱们得赶紧溜 这才两块五毛钱 你在说啥呢?
Marty, we gotta get the fuck out of here. It's $2.50. What are you talking about?
我要回来的可不止两块五 你没见刚才发生了什么?
I'm asking for way more than $2.50. You see what just happened?
在这等着 等着
Wait here. Wait.
- 等多久? - 十秒钟
- For how long? - Ten seconds.
我的鞋 我的衣服
My shoes, my clothes.
全湿透了 里面乱成一团
Everything's soaking wet. It's a mess in there.
- 你给我闭嘴吧 - 你想练练?
- Why don't you put a sock in it? - You wanna switch?
你! 我... 我早说了别用他妈的喷淋
You! I... I told you not to use the fucking shower.
你才没说 是你把房租给我的 懂吗?
No, you didn't. You're the one that rented me the room, okay?
我从天花板掉下来差点摔断脖子
I could have broken my neck falling out of that ceiling.
他妈的现在也还没准能摔断呢
That can fucking still happen too.
- 你现在是在威胁我吗? - 对 没错
- Are you threatening me right now? - Yeah, I am.
- 居然敢威胁我? - 对
- You want to threaten me? - Yeah.
- 地下室锁了! - 谁拿的他妈的钥匙?
- Basement is locked! - Who's got the fucking key?
听着 哥们! 听好了! 我要把房钱拿回来...
Listen, man! Listen! I want my money for my room...
- 救护车来了 - ...我还要赔偿
- Ambulance. - ...and I want a reimbursement
- 我那些毁了的破烂儿 - 认真的吗?
- for my shit that got ruined. - Are you serious?
你那些破玩意儿一个子儿也拿不回来
You're not gonna get your shit back.
- 七块五! - 你什么也别想拿
- $7.50! - You'll get nothing.
- 快点 帮帮我! - 医护人员来了
- Come on. Help me! - Paramedics.
- 好了 你们可来了 - 病人在哪儿?
- Good, you're here. - Where's the patient at?
在那儿 手臂受伤了 流了好多血
He's in here. It's his arm. He's lost a lot of blood.
怎么回事?
What happened?
- 浴缸砸他身上了 - 浴缸砸他身上了?
- Bathtub fell on him. - Bathtub fell on him?
我手没知觉了
I can't feel my arm.
哟 吉米 拜托 帮我把这狗弄走
Yo, Jimmy. Come on, you gotta help me with this dog.
- 我这儿没人手 - 得送它去兽医那儿
- I don't got nobody free. - We gotta get him to the vet.
- 我现在真腾不出人手 - 它是我的家人 哥们
- I got nobody free right now. - He's my family, man.
听着 把两块五还我 我就走 七块五不要了
Listen, now. Just give me the $2.50, and I'll get outta here. Forget the $7.50.
- 把两块五给我就行 - 我帮不了你
- Just give me $2.50. - I can't help you.
明天找老板去
See the owner tomorrow.
- 小子 - 都是因为这破旅馆的烂天花板
- Kid. - It's your shitty ceiling
- 给闹的 - 小子 噢!
- in this crummy hotel. - Kid. Oh!
- 我什么都不会给你 - 什么?
- I ain't giving you nothing. - What?
小子 拜托 把狗送去兽医那儿
Kid. Come on. Just bring the dog to the vet.
不行 我得工作 有活要干
I can't. I got work. I got a job.
- 我不能被开除 - 你有工作?
- I can't get fired. - You got a job?
- 我出双倍工钱 - 不 行不通 不行
- I'll give you double what you're getting. - No, I can't. I can't.
我给三倍 来吧
I'll give you triple. Come on.
- 悠着点 冷静下 - 行吧
- Take it easy. Calm down. - Okay.
行 翻下那个包 看到椅子上的包了吗?
Okay, look in that bag. See the bag on the chair?
对 翻那个包 把它打开
Yeah, go in that bag, okay? Open it up.
我得给你上个止血带
I'm gonna apply a tourniquet to you.
我这就把原来那个撤了
I'm gonna remove the other tourniquet right now.
拿五十给你自己 没错
Take 50 for yourself. Yeah.
再带五十给兽医 明白吗?
Bring 50 for the vet, okay?
血都喷出来了
We got blood squirting out.
他在13街和1大道交口
He's on 13th and 1st.
告诉他我一完事就赶过去 懂吗?
And tell him I'll be there as soon as I can get there, okay?
你居然要给这混蛋钱?
You're gonna give this motherfucker money?
是他他妈让浴缸砸到你身上的
He's the one who fuckin' dropped the tub on ya.
我警告过他别进那个破浴缸的
I told him not to get in the fuckin' bath.
真他妈讲究 小子
Fucking mensch, kid.
担架准备好了吗? 咱们送他去贝尔维尤
Stretcher ready? We'll take him to Bellevue.
真他妈讲究
Fucking mensch.
咱们现在掉头还来得及
We can still turn around
- 能送他去兽医那儿 - 不行 不行
- and take him to the vet. - No. No.
- 五十块钱绰绰有余了 - 知道什么比五十块更好吗? 一百块
- Fifty dollars is more than enough. - You know what's better than 50? 100.
有一百块本钱 咱们能赢个盆满钵满
We can clean house with a hundred.
别贪得无厌了 你这该死的犹太佬
Don't be greedy, you fucking Jew.
不 不 是1500美元的罚款 是你拿给我看的
No, no. It's a $1,500 fine. You're the one that showed it to me.
顺便说下 咱们得连续两周每晚都这么干
By the way, we gotta do this every night for two weeks,
- 否则我就去不了日本了 - "咱们"? 噢 不不不
- or else I can't go to Japan. - "We"? Oh, no, no, no.
我可不想因为你捅了娄子就两周不去上班
I'm not taking two weeks off work 'cause you fucked up.
嘿 拿着这个 伙计
Hey. Take this, boy.
拿着 没错 好孩子
Take this. There you go. Good boy.
把这混蛋的项圈松一松 伙计
Loosen up the collar on this motherfucker, man.
- 行了 - 他听着像个破暖气片
- All right. - He sound like a radiator.
咱们先去打球
We're gonna go play,
回来的路上再送他去兽医那儿
we'll drop him off at the vet on the way back.
- 耽搁两小时对他算得了什么? - 马蒂 我都约好车了 伙计
- What's a couple of hours to this guy? - Marty, I got rides set up, man.
唉 摩西
Huh. Moses.
三号球道 归你了
Lane three. That's you.
- 嘿 怎么样? - 有什么能帮您的?
- Hi, how you doing? - Could I help?
能给我开个球道吗?
Can I get a lane?
大概得等半小时 四十分钟
Probably gonna be a half hour, 40 minutes.
- 没问题 - 你确定能等?
- That's okay. - You all right with that?
- 要租鞋吗? - 我待会儿再拿
- You want shoes? - I'll just grab 'em later.
搞定 结束
Done. Over.
弱得可怜 给钱
Fucking pathetic. Pay up.
谁想打下一局?
Who wants next?
我能打吗? 嘿! 我能来一局吗?
Can I play? Hey! Can I play?
- 一块钱一局 - 行吧
- It's a dollar a game. - Okay.
- 你叫什么? - 塞思
- What's your name? - Seth.
来几个对攻热热身吧
Let's get a warm-up rally going.
不 要打就掏钱 否则闭嘴 我不打白工
Nah. Put up or shut up. I don't play for free.
行吧 没听过这规矩
All right. Never heard of that.
- 我押钱 - 他管账
- I'm holding. - He's holding.
你管账? 凭什么是他管?
You're holding? Why is he holding?
- 你带钱了吗? - 我能信任你吗?
- Have you got yours? - Can I trust you?
信任我 绝对没问题
Trust me, you can.
- 战况如何? - 好了 塞思对阵罗杰
- Where are we at? - All right, Seth vs. Roger.
一块钱一局
Dollar game.
我发球
I serve.
你干嘛呢? 我看都没看
What are you doing? I'm not even looking.
- 1比0 - 我刚才看都没看
- One-zip. - I wasn't even looking.
- 嘿 你不能那么干 - 啥?
- No, you can't do that. - What?
你得让球落到对面
You gotta let the ball hit the other side.
你不能用球拍接球 我得分
You can't catch it with your paddle. My point.
- 你说什么呢? - 你不能那么干
- What are you talking about? - You can't do that.
你得让球掉下桌子才行
You gotta let the ball fall off the table.
- 荒谬至极 - 你在耍赖
- That's ridiculous. - You're cheating.
- 我耍赖? - 对 这就叫耍赖
- I'm cheating? - Yeah, that's called cheating.
- 你没守规矩 - 行吧 分给你
- You're not following the rules. - Fine. Take the point.
谢谢 把球给我 1比1
- Thank you. Give me the ball. - One-one.
操
Fuck!
好险 打得好 打得好
- That was close. - That was good. That was good.
噢 不不不不不
Oh. No, no, no, no, no.
不不 拿走吧
No, no. Take it.
我本该让你五分的 伙计
I should have spotted you, like, five points, man.
你今天够倒霉了 留着吧
You've had a rough enough day already. Keep it.
谢谢 兄弟 谢谢
Thank you, brother. Thank you.
没事儿
It's all good.
打得不错
Good game.
好了 亚当 亚当 走着
All right, Adam. Adam, let's go.
你想押多少? 我能出五毛
- What do you want to put on? - I can go 50 cents.
你有球吗?
You got a ball?
你的鼻子怎么了?
What happened to your nose?
我有球 我有球
I got one, I got one.
有个乘客赖账跑了
Fare ran out on me.
赖什么账? 发生什么了?
Fare from what? What happened?
我是个计程车司机 曼哈顿来的
I'm a taxi driver. From Manhattan.
曼哈顿? 昂
- Manhattan? - Yeah.
那路费可不便宜 伙计
That's an expensive trip, man.
噢 可不是 二十 二十五块钱呢
Oh, yeah. $20, $25.
碰上有钱的主儿能给五块小费
Well, the high rollers tip five,
那就是五块小费 而且...
so that's five in tips. And...
我他妈刚送到地方 那家伙就勒住我
I fucking get to the spot, the guy chokes me out,
对着我后脑勺一顿猛拳 - 不会吧
- punching me in the back of the head. - No.
抢了我的钱拔腿就跑
Takes my money and run the fuck off.
后来我追上那混蛋 嘿 结果...
Caught up to the motherfucker, and, boy...
我把他揍得眼冒金星 伙计
I beat the brights off that motherfucker, man.
然后我搜了他全身
And I took what he had.
你把他搜刮了?
You took what he had?
那当然! 你他妈说对了
Hell, yeah! You fucking damn right.
你把那钱加进你的那叠钞票里了? 当然了
- You added that to your roll? - Sure did.
就在我刚才看你掏出的那厚厚一叠里
To that fat roll I've seen you pulling out.
这是原则 问题在于他妈的原则
It's principle. It's fucking principle!
我懂 我要是你就把它藏好
I understand that. I would keep it hidden.
在这儿这种地方 最好别露白
I would keep that down, if I were you, in this place.
我告诉你 可不是谁都像克里斯蒂安这么面善
Not everybody's as nice as Christian is, I'm telling you.
这就是我想说的
That's my point.
那在那儿坐着的混蛋又是谁?
What about that asshole right there?
我哪他妈知道那是谁
I don't know who the fuck that guy is.
你不能那样发球 怎么不能?
- You can't serve like that. - What do you mean?
我这么发球都好几年了
I've been serving like that for years.
嘿 罗杰 罗杰 嘿 太荒谬了
- Hey, Roger. Roger. Hello. - That's ridiculous.
再给我一分钟 我们的球道空出来了
- Give me one more minute. - Our lane is open.
球道能等 没事儿 不行 咱们得马上走
- The lane can wait. It's fine. - No, we gotta go now.
人家要让给别人了 我正打球呢
- They're gonna give it away. - I'm playing now.
我为了打保龄球等了一晚上 赶紧的 走啊
I have been waiting all night to bowl. Let's go. Come on.
罗杰 我得分
- Roger. - My point.
瞧瞧你干的好事
Look what you made me do.
我得走了
I gotta go.
- 你说你要走是什么意思? - 把那一块钱还我
- What do you mean you gotta go? - Give me my dollar back.
球还没打完呢
We're in the middle of a game.
那就算你弃权 把钱给我
You forfeit the game, then. Give me my dollar.
- 把钱还给我! - 别激动 退后点
- Give me my dollar back! - Relax. Back up, back up.
- 他要走人? - 你还没打完这局
- He's gonna leave the game? - You didn't finish the game.
行啊 那你来打 你来打
All right, then you play. Then you play.
我没钱了 伙计 最后十块都给他了
I'm broke, man. I gave him my last ten.
我跟你打
I'll play you.
喔 喔 喔
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哟 没想到你们也打乒乓球
Oh, wow. I didn't know you guys played table tennis.
出一块钱 你有一块钱吗?
Put up a dollar. Do you have a dollar?
- 操你 出五块 - 你哪来的五块钱
- Fuck you. Put up five. - You don't have five dollars.
噢 哇 你肯定是抢了谁吧
Oh, wow. You must have robbed someone.
少废话 拿钱说话
Put your money where your mouth is.
干脆我拿老二塞住你的嘴?
Why don't I put my penis where your mouth is?
红衣服的 沃利 还有他妈的随便谁
Red shirt, Wally and whatever the fuck his name is.
先记账 宝贝 我马上回来
Mark it blank, baby. I'll be right back.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
我会记账的!
I will mark it blank!
这儿干嘛呢?
What's going on here?
这黑小子要把钱输光了
The colored boy is about to lose all his money.
是啊 输给这混蛋了
Yeah, to this asshole right here.
- 操! - 赛点
- Fuck! - Match point.
- 赛点 来了 - 沃利! 加油!
- Match point. Here we go. - Wally! Come on!
别输不起啊 沃利 开始吧
Don't get upset though, Wally. Let's go.
好球!
Yeah!
擦边了 你他妈看到了
It grazed the edge. You fucking saw that.
没擦边
It didn't graze the edge.
- 球路变了 你看到了 - 没擦边
- It changed. You saw that. - It didn't graze the edge.
- 少废话 给钱 - 搞什么鬼?
- No, give me my money. - What the fuck?
- 把钱给我 - 这简直是...
- Give me my money. - This is b--
把钱给我 钱给我
Give me the money. Give me the money.
- 付钱 - 拜托了
- Pay me. - Come on.
留五块给我当油钱吧
Let me hold five for gas money.
不行 没钱就别瞎赌
No. You shouldn't bet with money you don't have.
- 我他妈怎么回家? - 走回去
- How the fuck am I gonna get home? - Walk.
就让他留五块吧
Just let him keep five.
- 不行 - 你整晚都像个烂人
- No. - You've been a dick all night.
- 给钱 - 别那么贪得无厌
- Give me my money. - Just stop being greedy.
- 给他五块回家吧! - 真是放屁!
- Just give him five to get home! - This is bullshit!
- 你他妈居然还笑 - 操你的!
- And you're fucking smiling. - Fuck you!
把钱给我 钱给我
Give me the money. Give me the money.
去你的
Fuck you.
- 喂 把那五块还他 - 我不想
- Yo, give him his five. - I don't want to.
我他妈到底怎么回家?
How the fuck am I gonna get home?
这就是满嘴喷粪的下场
That's what happens when you talk shit.
- 滋味不好受吧? - 操!
- It stinks, doesn't it? - Fuck!
- 罗杰呢? 罗杰在哪? - 该死
- Where's-- Where's Roger? - Shit.
- 是的 我在 - 来了 罗杰!
- Yeah, I got it. - Yeah, Rog!
跟这蠢货打一局 把他油钱赢回来
Play this numbnuts for his gas money.
现在你跟罗杰打 听到了吗?
You're gonna play Roger now, okay?
- 上吧 罗杰 - 上
- Let's go, Roger. - Let's go.
- 马上开始 - 你?
- Let's go right now. - You?
我不跟你打 你太厉害了
I won't play you. You're too good.
我让你四分
I'll spot you four points.
行赌四十块
Fine. Forty dollars.
四十块? 我没这么多钱
Forty dollars? I don't have forty dollars.
想打就打 不打拉倒 我得走了
You want it? Take it or leave it. I gotta go.
- 四十块 - 一 二 三...
- Forty dollars. - One, two, three...
快点 谁有现金? 谁有现钱?
Come on, who's got cash? Who's got cash?
- 我帮你 - 这是沃利队 加油
- I got you. - It's Team Wally. Come on.
凑一凑 凑一凑 让他有钱回家 快点
Pitch in, pitch in. Let's get him home. Come on, come on.
谢谢大家 谢谢
Thank you, everybody. Thank you.
我们会让你回家的 肯定让你回家
We're gonna get you home. We're gonna get you home.
太好了 这一排都没钱?
Great. Great. Nothing? This whole row?
嘿 我加个外注
Yo, I'll put a side bet.
多少?
How much?
- 五块 - 你就这点钱?
- Five dollars. - You don't got more than that?
十块 哟 还有点小钱嘛
Ten. Ooh, you got a little bit of money.
谢了 非常感谢
Thank you. Thanks so much.
174 175 176
One seventy-four, 175, 176,
177 178 179 180 181...
177, 178, 179, 180, 181...
♪ 因为我走了两百英里 ♪
♪ 'Cause I went 200 miles ♪
181 182 183...
181, 182, 183...
- 毛瑟回来了 宝贝 - ...184 185...
- The Mouse is back, baby. - ...184, 185...
- 噢耶! - ...186
- Yeah! - ...186
- 毛瑟回来了 宝贝! - ...187 192...
- The Mouse is back, baby! - ...187, 192...
- 噢 我最爱这段 - ...197 202 207...
- Oh, this is my part. - ...197, 202, 207...
你他妈在干什么?
What the fuck are you doing?
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
♪ 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah, wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah, wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah, wah, wah ♪
操 关门了
Fuck. It's closed.
- 去下个镇子吧 - 下个镇子? 那破地方开车要20分钟
- Let's just go to the next town. - Next town? That shit is 20 minutes away.
瞧瞧咱们干的 谁是乖孩子? 谁是乖孩子?
You see what we do? Who's a good boy? Who's a good boy?
- 400... - 过来 宝贝
- 400... - Come over here, baby.
...401 402 403...
...401, 402, 403...
他呼吸顺畅多了
His breathing's a lot better.
咱们也许不用给兽医送钱了
We might not have to give the vet any money.
...407 408
...407, 408.
408块 每人204块 咱俩平分
408. That's 204 each. That's 50-50.
给 拿着
Here, here. Okay.
沃利 我在想 如果你现在把钱全给我
Wally, I was thinking. If you give me the full amount now,
等我从日本回来能还你十倍
I can give you ten times that when I get back from Japan.
- 停 停下 毛瑟 - 别啊 什么意思?
- Stop, stop. Stop, Mouse. - No, no, what do you mean?
别想拿坑别人的那套来坑我
You're not gonna fuck me like you do everybody else.
- 你看到罚单了 你看到了 - 毛瑟
- You saw the fine. You saw it. - Mouse.
我回来的时候能带回十倍的钱
I'm gonna be coming home with ten times that.
- 我给你买个出租车牌照 - 我不他妈要什么牌照 毛瑟
- I'll buy you a medallion. - I don't want no fucking medallion, Mouse.
我给你买辆新出租 别在这事上跟我较劲
I'll buy you a new cab. Don't give me a hard time about this.
他在那儿!
There he is!
噢 操
Oh, fuck.
噢 操 马蒂 马蒂 快走 快上车
Oh, fuck. Marty. Marty, let's go. Get in the car.
- 好 让我来说 - 快上车!
- Okay, just let me do the talking. - Get in the car!
瞧瞧是谁! 搞死这王八蛋!
Look who it is! Let's get this motherfucker!
几位 晚上好
Gentlemen.
怎么了? 哥几个还好吧?
What's going on? How are we doing?
- 把钱还我们! - 你们在说什么?
- Give us our money! - What are you talking about?
- 我正给这位哥们加油呢 - 看看这是谁
- I'm giving this guy some gas. - Look who it is.
别玩这套!
Don't pull that shit!
- 你他妈设局千我们! - 我没千谁
- You fucking hustled us! - I didn't hustle anyone.
我认得你! 你是他妈的马蒂·毛瑟!
I know who you are! You're fuckin' Marty Mauser!
- 冷静点! - 我不认识那人!
- Relax! - I don't know who that is!
罗杰! 住手! 住手!
Roger! Stop it! Stop!
别 别冲动 有话好说
No, relax. Relax. Relax. Relax.
滚出这破车!
Out of the fucking car!
滚出这破车 你这黑鬼!
Get out of the fucking car, nigger!
- 凭什么要我... - 滚出来!
- Why I gotta be-- - Get the fuck out!
操!
Fuck!
- 马蒂 快他妈走! - 操你大爷!
- Marty, let's fucking go! - Fuck yourself!
走 走 走 走 快走
Go, go, go, go, go.
沃利 留神! 留神! 电线杆!
Wally, watch out! Watch out! The pole!
不! 不!
No! No!
沃利 狗 狗还在那 沃利
Wally, the dog. The dog, Wally.
- 去他妈的狗! - 我得带着狗!
- Fuck that dog! - I need the dog!
去他妈的狗
Fuck the dog,
- 也去你的 伙计! 去你的!
- and fuck you, man! Fuck you, man! - Oh, no. No!
他们会扣我工资的!
They'll take this out of my paycheck!
我车废了 伙计! 我他妈要丢工作了!
My car's fucked up, man! I'm gonna lose my fucking job!
这是我的全部! 我还有人要养呢!
This is all I got! I got people depending on me!
- 我有一大堆责任要担! - 我也有责任
- I got real responsibilities! - I got responsibilities too.
- 你屁个责任! - 你他妈觉得...
- No, you don't! - What the fuck you think--
♪ ...可能再次消融 ♪
♪ ...may melt again ♪
♪ 像那冬雪一般消融 ♪
♪ Like winter snow That melts ♪
♪ 伴随 ♪
♪ With ♪
♪ 四月的细雨 ♪
♪ April rain ♪
♪ 亲爱的 在我心底 ♪
♪ For darling, in my heart ♪
♪ 你将永远常驻 ♪
♪ You always will remain ♪
♪ 随着夏去秋来 ♪
♪ As summer turns to fall ♪
多谢了 谢谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
我会补偿你的 好吗?
I'm gonna make it up to you. All right?
别生我气 行吗?
Don't be mad at me. Okay?
我会给你买辆新出租的 真的
I'm gonna get you a new cab. All right?
别担心 沃利 我爱你
Don't worry about it. Wally, I love you.
帮我关个门
Close my door.
嘿 马蒂
Hey, Marty.
- 嘿 泰德 - 嘿 马蒂 伙计 近来可好?
- Hey, Ted. - Hey, Marty. How you doing, man?
- 劳伦斯在吗? - 节哀顺变
- Is Lawrence here? - Sorry about your loss.
没事的 劳伦斯今晚在这儿吗?
It's all right. Is Lawrence here tonight?
昂 在 就在这附近哪个地儿
Uh, yeah. He's around here somewhere.
- 好的 知道了 谢了 - 行 行
- Okay. All right. Thank you. - Yeah, yeah.
- 见到你很高兴 伙计 - 嗯
- Good to see you, man. - Yep.
- 最近怎么样? - 马蒂
- How you been? - Marty.
- 见到你真好 - 嘿 马蒂
- Nice to see you. - Hello, Marty.
嘿 今晚能借住你的后屋吗 求你了?
Hey, can I stay in your back room tonight, please?
嘿 嘿 你的小妞在后头呢 知道吗?
Hey, hey. Got your girl in the back, okay?
她怀孕了 情绪特别糟
She pregnant. She real upset.
噢 天哪 好吧 知道了
Oh, God. Okay. All right.
额 我去跟她谈谈
Uh, let me go talk to her,
但在见我之前 麻烦千万别走开
but then please don't leave without finding me.
- 放心 我就在这儿 - 好 很高兴见到你
- Yeah, I'll be here. Okay. - All right. Nice to see you.
- 好的 很高兴见到你 - 嗯
- All right, good to see you. - Okay.
嘿 你怎么在这儿?
Hey. What are you doing here?
我没想打扰你 我知道你很忙
I don't mean to bother you. I know you're really busy.
- 你脸是怎么搞的? - 我真的没别的地方去了
- What the hell happened to your face? - I didn't really have anywhere else to go.
- 让我看看 - 他突然就开始...
- Let me see. - He just started...
他突然就开始对我吼
he just started yelling at me.
他疯了一样 还扯我的衣服
And he was really mad and he was ripping my clothes.
- 他把你弄成这样的? - 他真的吓死我了
- He did this to you? - He was really scaring me.
我只是不知道还能去哪儿
I just didn't know where else to go.
你在生我的气吗?
Are you mad at me?
瑞秋?
Rachel?
不 不是瑞秋 是马蒂 开门
No, it's not Rachel. It's Marty. Open the door.
嘿 迪昂 怎么样 伙计? 真的很感谢
Hey, Dion. How you doing, man? I really appreciate this.
顺便说下 这是我妹妹瑞秋
This is my sister Rachel, by the way.
瑞秋 这是我哥们 也是生意伙伴 迪昂
Rachel, this is my buddy, my business partner, Dion.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
她那儿淹水了
Her place flooded.
她得在这儿凑合一晚 没问题吧?
She needs a place to crash for the night. That's okay, right?
我不确定 伙计 这...
I don't know, man, it's...
我知道 但我不能让她待在有霉菌孢子什么的破地儿
I know, but I can't have her exposed to mold and spores and shit.
迪 拜托 她都怀孕八个月了 懂吗?
D, come on, she's eight months pregnant, all right?
拜托...
Come on...
那可是我亲外甥
That's my nephew.
我不该带人回来的
I'm not supposed to have people over.
她家里情况很糟 我不能让她回去 求你了
She's got a bad situation at home. I can't have her going back there. Please.
行吧 进来吧 你可以住一晚
All right. Come on. You can spend the night.
但明天我爸妈回来前你得离开
You just gotta be out of here by tomorrow before my parents get back.
没问题
Okay. No problem.
咱们得趁聚在一起把时间利用好
We should take advantage of the time we have together.
好好敲定咱们的业务计划
You know, really firm up our business plan.
这样你爸回来就能看到咱们有多专业了
That way, when your dad gets back, he sees how organized we are.
是啊 他现在挺火大的
Yeah, he's pretty upset.
你把这堆库存丢给咱们八个月没管
You left us with all of this inventory for eight months.
没关系 几周后我拿下冠军
That's fine. In a few weeks I'll take the championship.
咱们就能重回正轨
We'll be right back on track.
- 球就在这儿 - 真的? 哪呢?
- Balls are right in here. - Really? Where?
最上面的箱子
The top box.
谢了
Thanks.
- 哇 你做了橙色的?
- Whoa. You did the orange? - Yep.
你怎么做成橙色的?
How'd you do the orange?
我联系了海力士的人
I contacted someone at Halex.
他们帮我给赛璐珞上了色
They colored the celluloid for me.
- 怎么搞定的? - 靠钱呗 宝贝
- How? - Money, baby.
我和我老爸都看好你
Me and my pop, we believe in you.
我们投了钱的 这就是他一直火大的原因
We're invested. That's why he's been so mad.
瞧瞧这个 瑞秋
Check it out, Rachel.
来 看看这包装
Here, check out the packaging.
"马蒂至尊 马蒂·毛瑟锦标赛官方乒乓球
"Marty Supreme. The official Marty Mauser championship table tennis ball.
专业制造 橙色..."
Professionally made. Orange..."
橙色球体? 你想出来的?
Orange spheres? You came up with that?
是啊 挺棒的吧?
Yeah. Pretty good, right?
何止棒啊 迪昂 这... 我惊呆了
Pretty good? Dion, this is... I'm stunned.
太震撼了
I'm stunned.
- 还是手绘的 - 你画的?
- Hand-drawn too. - You drew this?
- 对 - 真是神来之笔
- Yeah. - It's inspired.
多谢夸奖
I appreciate it.
你都不知道自己多有能耐
I don't think you know what you're capable of.
- 你看 - 真的多谢
- Check it out. - Thanks a lot.
哇
Wow.
真的很漂亮
it's really nice.
- 这是你的房间? - 不是 是我弟弟的
- This is your room? - No, it's my brother's.
你还有弟弟? 你从来没跟我说过
You have a brother? You never told me you had a brother.
是个亲弟弟 已经搬走了
It's a younger brother. He moved out.
那他房间空着?
So his room is free?
- 额 对 - 我先去安顿一下我妹
- Uh, yeah. - Let me get my sister situated.
- 五分钟后去找你 - 行
- I'll come find you in five minutes. - Okay.
五分钟
Five minutes.
迪昂 你真让我刮目相看
I'm really impressed, D.
- 谢谢 - 说真的
- Thank you. - Seriously.
真是个特别的人
Special guy.
我把床给你弄舒服点 好吗?
Let me get the bed comfortable for you, all right?
那你现在要出去吗?
So are you gonna go out there now?
对 我得琢磨下明天的计划
Yeah, I gotta figure my plan out for tomorrow.
为什么? 什么计划?
Why? Plan for what?
我得理理头绪
Well, I need to get my head together.
怎么说?
How so?
有个有钱佬找我干活 我打算联系他
This rich guy hit me up for a job. I think I'm gonna get in touch with him.
- 真的? - 是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
- 干什么活? 什么工作? - 不重要 能去日本就行
- A job for what? What job? - It doesn't matter. Just to get to Japan.
- 为了锦标赛? - 对
- For the championship? - Yeah.
哇
Wow.
虽然生活一团糟 但我会搞定的
Everything in my life is falling apart, but I'm gonna figure it out.
需要帮忙吗? 我可以帮你
Do you need any help? I could help you.
- 没事 不用了 - 我能做点什么吗?
- No, it's all right. It's all right. - Can I do anything?
你饿吗?
Are you hungry?
- 不饿 - 确定?
- No. - You sure?
额 我去另一个房间待着 行吗?
Uh, I'll just be in the other room, all right?
- 迪昂 我从没见过这种球 - 我就说吧 伙计
- Dion, I've never seen anything like this. - I told you, man.
伙计 咱们得好好叙叙旧
Man, we have to have a big catch-up
因为这是八个月来发生在我身上最伟大的事
'cause this is the greatest thing that's happened to me in the last eight months.
谁能想到呢? 海力士?
Who would've thought? Halex?
早上好 洛克威尔油墨公司
Good morning. Rockwell Ink.
是的 你好 请帮我接米尔顿·洛克威尔先生
Yes, hi, can I speak to Milton Rockwell, please?
他现在不在 需要留个言吗?
He's not in at the moment. Can I take a message?
好吧 什么时候能联系到他?
Okay, when are you expecting him?
额 他今天在外面办公
Well, he's working off-site today.
- 再问一遍 需要留言吗? - 趁热喝
- Again, can I take a message?- It's hot.
太感谢了
Thank you so much.
等我妹醒了 能给她也弄点吗?
Can you make some for my sister for when she wakes up?
- 她会很饿的 - 喂?
- She'll be really hungry. - Hello?
你说他在外面哪儿?
You said off-site where?
抱歉 我不能告诉你相关信息
I'm sorry, I can't give you that information.
- 您到底要不要留言? - 要
- Would you like to leave a message or not?- Yes.
能替我向他道个歉吗?
Can you apologize to him on my behalf?
我是原本今早要和他
I was the young gentleman that was supposed to have breakfast
一起吃早餐的那个年轻人
with him this morning.
- 我不清楚 - 就是他儿子那个营的
- I'm not familiar.- From his son's battalion.
抱歉 我对此一无所知
I'm sorry, I-- I don't know anything about that.
我这儿有他儿子的个人遗物 应该交给他
I have some personal belongings of his son's I was supposed to give to him.
信件 纪念品之类的 但我搞砸了 睡过头了
Letters and mementos and such, but I messed up and I overslept.
我今天就要离开这儿 要不邮寄给他更方便?
I'm leaving town today, but I could mail it to him if that's easier.
- 不 不行 - 不行? 好的
- No, no, no.- No? Okay.
这样吧 你试试往莫罗斯科剧院打个电话
How about this, why don't you try giving a call over to the Morosco Theatre.
莫罗斯科剧院
The Morosco Theatre.
所以我算什么? 我在干嘛?
So, I'm like what? What am I doing?
跑这儿来毁了我的夜晚
Coming up here to wreck my night.
说真的 妈 我压根不知道你会来
Honest, Mama, I didn't even know you were coming here.
我受够了你耍花招
I'm through with you playing games.
我只是来找点乐子
I was just coming for a good time.
我听说应召女郎都在这儿扎堆
I heard this was where all the call girls gather.
我正努力重建生活 你不明白吗?
I'm trying to rebuild my life here. Don't you understand that?
我看是把自己卖给出价最高的人吧
More like selling out to the highest bidder.
你没资格评判我 杰德
You've got no right to judge me, Jed.
我拼尽全力才换来那么一点幸福
I fought tooth and nail for every shred of happiness
- 哪怕只有一点... - 对 那你给过我什么?
- I've ever found while you... - Right, and what did you give to me?
你从没相信过我 一次都没有!
You never believed in me. Not once!
你想沉溺于自怜吗? 杰德 烤箱在那儿呢!
You wanna wallow in self-pity? Well, here's an oven, Jed!
阿尔玛!
Alma!
我没事 亨利
I'm all right, Henry.
- 请给我们留点私人时间 - 我妈就是个烂货
- Just give us a minute, please. - My mama is a dirty bird.
嘴放干净点 杰迪代亚
Be careful now, Jedidiah.
你给她穿的那身华丽衣裳 只是掩盖她身上的臭味!
And that fancy dress you put her in is the only thing keeping in the stench!
不许碰我孩子
Don't you lay a hand on my child.
我... 抱歉 额...
I-I'm sorry, uh...
妈 我做错什么了?
Mama, what did I do?
走! 快跑!
Go! Run!
- 门锁了 - 噢 我的天
- The door is locked. - Oh, my God.
开什么玩笑!
You've gotta be kidding me!
搞什么鬼 谁给这门加了插销?
For Christ's sake, did somebody put a latch on the door?
- 噢天呐 - 我以为刚才节奏挺好的
- Oh, God. - I thought we had a good rhythm going.
节奏挺好? 你住哪个星球啊 节奏算哪门子好
A good rhythm going? On what planet is that a good rhythm
- 如果你就自个儿在那演? - 我入戏了
- if you're alone in a room? - I was in it.
搞得跟我不在场一样 入戏? 戏在哪呢?
It's like I wasn't even there. In it? In what?
- 格伦 我一句话都插不上 - 我懂 咱们会修正的
- Glenn, I couldn't get a word out. - I understand. We're gonna fix it.
- 排练过程就是为了解决这些 - 真他妈绝了
- That's what a rehearsal process is for. - Fuck's sake.
先停一下吧 大家休息五分钟
Let's lose this, by the way. Everybody take five.
帮个忙 各位...
Do me a favor, everybody...
得有人跟他说说这事
Somebody needs to tell him something.
- 简直离谱 - 不可理喻
- It's impossible. - Impossible.
- 喝水吗? - 喝
- Do you want some water? - Yes.
- 我去给你拿点 - 天哪
- Let me bring you some. - God.
嘿 凯
Hey, Kay.
嘿 是马蒂
Hey, it's Marty.
伦敦那个
From London.
你怎么跑这儿来了?
What are you doing here?
额 我有个舞台技师协会的朋友
Well, I got a friend in the stagehands union.
我过来给他送点东西
I was dropping something off for him.
- 你刚才看了? - 是的 希望没冒犯到你
- You watched that? - Yeah, I hope that's okay.
噢 天呐
Oh, God.
嘿 没想到你又开始演戏了
Hey, I can't believe you're acting again.
那不叫演戏 他压根不让我演
That wasn't acting. He won't let me act.
嗯 看得出来挺闹心的 那家伙什么来头?
Yeah, no, that looked frustrating. What's the deal with that guy?
别提了
Don't get me started.
是啊 你刚才演技完全吊打他
Yeah, you were running circles around him.
那是当然
Of course I am.
确实 简直神了
Yeah. It was unbelievable.
他连续三天不睡觉
He stays up for three days in a row
就因为他的角色应该很疲惫
because his character is supposed to be tired.
- 简直不可理喻 - 噢天呐
- It's obnoxious. - Oh, God.
要是他真那么投入 为什么要停下来?
If he's so committed, why'd he stop the scene?
他干嘛不一拳打穿那个帘子
Why didn't he punch his hand through the screen,
从里面把锁打开?
unlock it from the other side?
- 对吧? 换我会这么干 - 格伦!
- Right? That's what I would've done. - Glenn!
- 来了 - 格伦!
- Yeah. - Glenn!
- 好的 来了 - 我有话跟你说
- Yes. Thank you. Yes. - I need to talk to you.
- 怎么了? - 什么?
- Yes, what? - What? What? What?
这小子比他更懂这个角色
This kid understands the character better than he does.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
- 把你刚才跟我说的话告诉他 - 不 我不想说
- Tell him what you just told me. - No, I don't want to.
说吧 告诉他
No, tell him.
我只是觉得你刚才看起来没入戏 仅此而已
I was just saying you didn't really seem like you were in the scene is all.
- 额 这位是谁? - 他谁也不是 关键就在这儿
- Uh, who is this? - He's nobody. That's the point.
而且 以我的经验 只有小孩才会那样拿刀
Also, you know, in my experience, only children hold a knife like this.
要是真打 刀应该这么拿
If it's a serious fight, you hold your knife like this,
- 刀刃要垂直于手腕 - 这又不是街头斗殴
- with the blade square to your wrist. - This is not a street fight.
好吧 如果你不追求真实感的话
Okay, well, if you're not going for realistic,
那你还得再加点花样
you might as well add a little flair.
就像这样
Like that.
- 别闹了 - 对吧 凯?
- Cut it out. - Right, Kay?
行了 行了 谢了您的教程 非常感谢
Okay. Yeah, okay. Thanks for the tutorial. Thank you very much.
真是太感谢了 今天就到这吧 谢谢
Thank you very much indeed. That's all we need today. Thank you.
- 祝你好运 凯 万事顺利 - 让他滚出去!
- Best of luck, Kay. Best of luck. - Get him out!
这里不需要你了 非常感谢
We no longer require your presence. Thank you very much.
恕我直言...
Well, with all due respect...
可每套布景都要花掉五千多块
And yet every set cost more than $5,000.
我没法打个响指 就把你老婆和钱都搞顺当
I can't just snap my fingers and get your money and your wife into alignment.
我付你钱是让你想办法的
I pay you to say no.
她似乎觉得这是在拿空头支票开玩笑
She seems to think that this is carte blanche.
我没法在这里完成不可能的任务
I can't just perform the impossible here.
如果你管不住她 我就找个能管住的人来
If you can't control her, I will find someone else who can.
混蛋
Asshole.
洛克威尔先生 洛克威尔先生
Mr. Rockwell. Mr. Rockwell.
- 干什么? - 嘿 马蒂·毛瑟 见到你真好
- What? - Hey. Marty Mauser. Nice to see you.
是你往我办公室打电话 说是跟我儿子是哥们的?
Did you call my office and say you're friends with my son?
- 是的 但是... - 该死!
- Yes. But... - Goddamn it!
我没别的办法联系你了 拜托
I had no other way to get in touch with you. Please.
我想重新谈谈去日本的事
I wanna revisit our conversation about Japan.
我重新考虑过了 我想去 我觉得那是绝佳的主意
I reconsidered it and I wanna do it. I think it's a great idea.
比赛就在下周 我已经有别的打算了
The event's next week. I've made alternate plans.
什么打算? 嘿 那可是你的主意
What other plans? Okay, it was your idea.
这主意棒极了 咱们就花两秒钟谈谈这事吧
It's a fantastic idea. Let's just have a conversation about this for two seconds.
你干什么呢? 嘿 嘿 洛克威尔先生
What are you doing? Hey. Hey. Mr. Rockwell.
拜托 咱们都现实一点好吗
Please, let's both be pragmatists about this.
把你对我的个人成见先放一边
Put your personal feelings about me aside for a second.
你我都很清楚 我和远藤古都打能创造多大价值
You and I both know how much value I would add with Endo.
在他的主场打表演赛?
In an exhibition on his home turf?
想象一下 我就像根炸药引信
Imagine it. I'd be like a stick of dynamite.
不管你现在的备选方案是什么
Whatever you have planned, the alternative,
跟这个比起来都黯然失色
it's gonna pale in comparison.
请给我两分钟时间
Please give me two minutes.
咱们有很多共识能解决这问题 拜托!
We have enough common ground to figure this out. Please!
- 行吧 上车说 - 真的? 谢谢
- All right, get in the car. - Really? Thank you.
汤米 开车
Tommy, let's go.
- 嘿 嘿! 嘿! - 嘿!
- Hey. Hey! Hey! - Hey!
你个狗娘养的 那个主意还是我给你的!
You son of a bitch. I gave you the idea!
不好意思 斯通小姐让我转告你
I'm sorry. Miss Stone wanted to let you know
她很乐意和你共进午餐
that she'd love to have lunch with you.
- 斯通小姐? - 是的
- Miss Stone? - Yes.
天哪 我迟到太久了
My God, I'm so late.
拜托 你管那么多干嘛?
Come on. What do you care?
你可是主角 这感觉应该很爽吧?
You're the star. Gotta feel pretty good, right?
我是说 你当初为什么要息影?
I mean, why'd you even stop in the first place?
我想要稳定 后来我怀孕了
I wanted security, and I got pregnant,
加上他的压力 我就妥协了
and he pressured me, and I settled.
嗯 显然你现在做的是正确决定
Well, I mean, clearly, you're doing the right thing now
而且听起来他正加倍补偿你呢
and it sounds like he's paying you back with interest.
- 谁? - 你丈夫
- Who is? - Your husband.
我是说 你的整场演出都是他出钱吧?
I mean, he's funding your whole show, right?
你哪来的这种想法?
Where'd you get that idea?
我在大堂无意中听到他在抱怨
I overheard him complaining about it in the lobby.
- 抱怨? - 是的 抱怨开销太大
- Complaining? - Yeah, about the costs.
让他滚一边去吧
He can go fuck himself.
没错 彻底滚蛋 你知道你该怎么做
Completely. You know what you should do,
你应该榨干他的每一分钱
you should leech him for every penny he's worth,
坐稳你全球头号巨星的位子
assume your place as the biggest star on the planet,
然后狠狠打他那张自大嘴脸
and then you rub it in his smug little face.
谢谢 但我真的不需要你来教我做事
Thank you, but I'm really not looking for life advice from you.
不 我只是说你打从一开始就不需要他
No, I'm just saying you clearly never needed him in the first place.
就像我 我从不接受任何人的帮助
Like with me, I'm never accepting anyone's help.
我得完全靠自己 纯粹靠我自己的天赋
I gotta do it completely on my own. Purely on the basis of my own talent.
否则的话 这种成功就不算数了
Otherwise it's, like, the success won't even count.
不过这只是我个人的想法
But that's just me.
是的 这种话听起来倒是容易
Yes, well, that's very easy to say.
说起来容易 做起来可真难
Well, it's easy to say but it's sure not easy to do.
我是说 你懂的 所以你才拿钱退出了
I mean, you know that. That's why you cashed out.
我问你个事
Let me ask you something.
你搞这种乒乓球的小玩意儿能挣钱吗?
Do you make money at this little table tennis thing?
- 还没呢 - 你有工作吗?
- Not yet. - Do you have a job?
没有 我是说 乒乓球就是我的工作
No. I mean, table tennis is my job.
那你靠什么生活?
How do you live?
我靠信念活着
I live with the confidence
只要我相信自己 钱自然会来的
that if I believe in myself, the money will follow.
归根结底 我的奋斗不全是为了钱
Ultimately, my struggle isn't even about money.
- 你怎么交房租? - 我不交
- How do you pay rent? - I don't.
- 你在回避问题 - 不 我没回避任何事
- You're avoiding the question. - No, I'm not avoiding anything.
那你今天打算怎么解决吃饭问题?
How do you plan on eating food today?
说实话 打算等你一走我就叫客房服务
Honestly, I was gonna order room service the second you leave.
- 漂亮 - 确实 漂亮
- Nice. - Yeah. Nice.
如果你这整套梦想最终没成 你打算怎么办?
And what do you plan to do if this whole dream of yours doesn't work out?
我压根就没考虑过这种可能
That doesn't even enter my consciousness.
行吧 也许你应该考虑下
Okay. Well, maybe it should.
哇
Wow.
你听起来像我妈 无意冒犯
You sound like my mom. No offense.
你听起来像个小屁孩
And you sound like a child.
噢 是吗? 显然我年纪够大了
Oh, yeah? Clearly I'm old enough.
你什么意思?
And what is that supposed to mean?
意思就是我年纪够大 可以在你复出的节骨眼
That I'm old enough to fuck you in your hotel room
在你酒店房间里把你办了
in the middle of your big comeback.
你真恶心
You're disgusting.
祝演出顺利
Break a leg.
不 我知道 但我当时出城了
No, I know, but I was out of town
所以我昨天才刚收到那份东西
so I only just received it yesterday for the first time.
听着 不去日本是不可能的
Well, look, not coming to Japan is not an option.
好吧 请转告赛斯先生 全额的银行本票
Okay, well, just let Mr. Sethi know that a cashier's check in the full amount
已经在路上了 已经寄出了
is already on the way to him. It's in the mail.
不 没关系的 但只是...
No, that's fine, but just...
我不希望有人对我到场有误会
I don't want any confusion about my attendance.
我会准时出席 比赛开始我就在那儿
I'm gonna be there. I'm gonna be there when the tournament starts.
- 拿到了! - 耶! 太棒了!
- I got it! - Yes! Yes! Yes!
你觉得值多少?
How much do you think?
- 这东西是假的 - 你说什么叫是假的?
- This is not real. - What do you mean it's not real?
- 彻头彻尾的假货 - 这可是从千万富婆脖子上摘下来的
- Total fake. - It came from the neck of a millionaire.
我亲眼看着从她脖子上摘下的
I saw it come off her neck.
我不管哪来的 这就是垃圾
I don't care where it came from. It's total garbage.
- 廉价首饰 - 廉价首饰?
- Costume jewelry. - Costume jewelry?
噢 操
Oh, fuck.
你想要的话 我可以出两块钱收了
If you want, I can give you two bucks for it.
- 喂? - 嘿 迪昂 是我
- Hello.- Hey, Dion. It's me.
你怎么样?
How are you doing?
嘿 你跑哪去了? 你答应过要弄到经销商名单的
Hey, where have you been? You promised me we'd have a list of distributors.
我爸今晚就落地了
My dad lands tonight.
我这就回去 全力配合你
I'll come back now and give you my undivided attention.
先让我跟我妹说两句
Let me just talk to my sister for a second.
瑞秋 马蒂来电话了
Rachel, Marty's on the phone.
- 嗨 你在哪呢? - 嗨 瑞秋 听着
- Hi. Where are you?- Hi, Rachel, listen.
我夹克里有个狗项圈 明白吗?
There's a dog collar in my jacket, okay?
我认识个在新泽西丢了狗的家伙
I know a guy who lost a dog out in New Jersey.
他会付大笔赏金
He'll pay a big reward.
还有 正门口碗里有一串车钥匙
Also, there's a set of car keys in a bowl by the front door.
- 见着了吗? - 见到了
- You see them?- Yeah.
把钥匙拿上 别让迪昂瞧见
Grab the keys, and make sure Dion doesn't see you do it.
嘿 迪昂
Hey, Dion.
能去商店帮我买点生姜吗?
Can you go to the store and grab me some ginger?
我晨吐反应特别厉害
I'm having really bad morning sickness.
嗨
Hi.
抱歉 油站关门了
Sorry, station's closed.
没事 我们不是来加油的
That's okay. We're not looking for service.
你看见这附近有狗出没吗?
Did you see a dog come around here?
没 啥也没见着 你瞧见狗了吗?
Nah, I ain't seen nothing. You seen a dog?
- 差不多这么高 - 什么时候丢的?
- He's this tall. - When did you lose it?
几天前
A few days ago.
克兰伯里有个收容所 往那走大概五英里
There's a pound down in Cranberry. About five miles that way.
- 也许去那试试 - 我打过电话了
- Maybe try there. - I called there.
- 抱歉 帮不上忙 - 好吧
- Sorry, can't help you. - Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
他们什么也没瞧见
They didn't see anything.
咱们去那儿试试
Let's go try that place.
你好
Hello.
有人吗?
Hello?
- 你去哪? - 我去后面瞧瞧
- Where are you going? - Just gonna check out back.
噢 操 摩西
Oh, shit. Moses.
我们非常感谢全国各地的唱片商和艺术家们
We're grateful to the record manufacturers and artists
全国各地的艺术家们
all over the country.
嘿 伙计 嘿 嘿 摩西
Hey, buddy. Hey. Hey, Moses.
是我 马蒂 嘿 伙计 噢 操
It's Marty. Hey, buddy. Oh, fuck.
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
摩西 摩西!
Moses. Moses!
嘿 伙计 冷静点 咱们带你回家
Hey, buddy. Calm down. Let's get you home.
你想回家的 对吧? 咱们回家
You wanna go home, right? Let's go home.
好了 嘿 别别别别别
Okay. Hey. No, no, no, no, no.
刚才为您播放的是佩珀敏特·哈里斯
And that was Peppermint Harris
以及他的那首金曲...
and that great record of his...
不过现在是时候暂别这档节目了
But it's time to hang up the old blunderbuss for now.
记住 如果你想...
Remember, if you want any...
- 嗨 你好? - 有什么事?
- Hi, how are you? - Can I help you?
我们正帮附近丢了狗的人找狗
We were just searching the area for a lost dog.
- "我们"? - 我和我丈夫
- "We"? - My husband and I.
我们的狗几天前在加油站附近丢了
We lost our dog a couple of days ago out near the gas station
他们叫我们来这边瞧瞧...
and they told us to come and check over here...
- 既然你是最近的一户人家 - 谁?
- seeing that you're the closest house. - Who?
谁? 哪个加油站?
Who? Which gas station?
- 我不知道 - 嘿!
- I don't know. - Hey!
是那里一个工作的伙计说的
It was one of the guys that work there.
- 噢 伙计 看到你回来真激动 - 他就在那儿!
- Oh, man, I'm so excited you're back. - There he is!
- 我觉得你可能找到了我们的狗 - 你们在私闯民宅
- I think you might've found our dog. - You're trespassing.
不 抱歉 我们没那意思 我们听到后院有狗叫
No. I'm sorry, that's not our intention. We heard barking in the back.
我压根不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我的狗 你找到了
My dog. You found it.
我没找着什么狗
I didn't find any dog.
你确定?
Are you sure?
废话 我确定 你确定?
Yeah, I'm sure. Are you sure?
是啊...
Yeah...
我看了你的窗户
I looked through your window.
- 我看到我的狗了 - 你居然窥探我的窗户?
- I saw my dog. - You were looking through my window?
幸亏我看了 不是吗?
It was a good thing I did, right?
在我叫警察之前 赶紧从我的地盘滚出去
Get the hell off my property before I call the police.
该叫警察的是我
I should call the police.
行啊 你想近距离看看他吗?
Okay. You wanna get a closer look at him?
- 你想近距离看看? - 是的 求你了
- You wanna closer look? - Yes, please.
- 行 挺好 - 我就让你看个够
- Okay, good, good. - I'll give you a closer look.
嘿!
Hey!
冷静点
Calm down.
我很冷静
I am calm.
- 要是再让我看到你这张犹太脸... - 你认真的?
- If I see your kike face... - Are you serious?
- ...再敢窥探我的窗户 - 马蒂 快上车!
- ...looking through my window again... - Marty, get in the car!
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
...我就开枪把它崩了
...I'm gonna shoot it off.
没必要那样 我们这就走 马蒂 快上车!
There's no need for that. We're leaving. Marty, get in!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
- 钱太多了 太多了 - 不 直接说 他他妈有的是钱
- It's too much money. It's too much. - No, say it. He's fucking loaded.
- 喂? - 告诉他
- Hello?- Tell him.
我在想 拿两千块钱还算公道
I was thinking maybe $2,000 seems fair for this kind of a thing.
我觉得挺公道的
That seems pretty fair to me.
- 两千 - 你开玩笑呢吧?
- Two thousand. - You're joking, right?
- 没开玩笑 - 简直他妈的离谱
- No, no. No. - That's fucking ridiculous.
听着 听着...
Look, look...
我知道这事跟你没关系
I know it's really not your problem,
但我快生了 而且 瞧 我现在也没丈夫
but I'm about to have a baby, and, look, I got no husband right now.
我没工作 这笔钱真的 真的能帮到我
I got no job, and this money would really, really help me.
而且 你懂的 咱们都是好人...
And, you know, let's be good people and...
你知道那条狗是我从收容所免费领的 对吧?
You realize I got that dog for free at the pound, right?
额 那你这看法可就不对了
Well, that's kind of the wrong way to look at it.
- 噢 是吗? - 是的 真的
- Oh, really?- Yeah, really.
那我该怎么看?
How am I supposed to look at it?
咱们就这么说吧 我现在打这电话不是为了狗
'Cause let's just say that I'm not calling about a dog.
假设我这电话是为你妈打的
Let's say that I'm calling about your mother,
我是个医生 我得给她做急诊手术
and I'm a doctor, and I gotta perform emergency surgery on her
否则她就没命了 你会怎么做?
or she's gonna die. What are you gonna do?
就因为你妈也是"免费"来的 你就拒绝手术?
Refuse the surgery because you got your mother for free?
不! 那太疯了 你肯定会同意手术
No! That's crazy. You're gonna take the surgery
- 因为你爱你妈 - 这是我听过最蠢的话
- because you love your mother. - That's the stupidest thing I ever heard.
那我看你压根不懂什么是爱
Well, then I guess you don't know anything about love.
行了 别扯了 给我地址 好吗? 我现在就过去
All right, forget it. Give me your address, okay? I'll come now.
- 我带现金过去 - 抱歉 但不行
- I'll bring you the cash.- I'm sorry, but no.
- 不行? - 不行
- No?- No.
这真的不是你的错 听起来你也是个大好人
it's really not your fault, and you sound like a very nice person.
只是我以前被坑过太多次了
It's just I've been ripped off one too many times in the past,
我再也不想让那种事发生了
and I'm just not willing to let that happen to me again.
所以 咱们得想个办法 让我先拿到钱
So, we're just gonna need to find a way to get me the money first.
- 你懂吗? 对 - 真的吗?
- You know? Yeah. - Yeah?
给我听好了 你这个他妈的臭娘们
Listen to me, you fucking dumb bitch.
- 你一分钱也别想拿到... - 你有什么毛病?
- You're not getting one red cent...- What is wrong with you?
...除非我亲眼见到它
...without me laying eyes on him.
- 如果你真的不在乎... - 听明白了吗 妹子?
- If you really don't give a shit about... - You understand, sister?
...你那只白捡的狗 没准我该把它捐给医学界做研究?
...your dog that you got for free, how about I donate him to medical science?
- 你想要那种结果吗? - 我就说这行不通
- Would that be something you want? - I told you this wasn't gonna work.
我早该知道的 我在干什么啊?
I should have known better. What am I doing?
- 真是个烂主意 - 马蒂!
- It was a terrible idea. - Marty!
- 蠢透了 - 抱歉 我当时想...
- It was moronic. - I'm sorry, I was--
抱歉 我只是想试一把
I'm sorry. I was trying to give it a shot.
- 不是你的错 是这事太蠢了 - 好了 冷静点
- It's not your fault. It was stupid. - All right. Calm down.
那狗是什么颜色的?
What color is the dog?
干嘛? 谁在乎啊 是棕色的
Why? Who cares? It's brown.
好吧 因为我老板认识当地所有的育犬师
Okay, because my boss knows all of the local breeders,
没准咱们能找只长得一样的
and maybe we can get one that looks the same,
主人肯定分不出区别
and the owner won't be able to tell the difference.
你觉得他会认不出他心爱的狗?
You don't think he's gonna recognize his own dog that he loves?
- 我是说起码一开始认不出 - 我现在本该在练球
- I'm saying maybe not at first. - I should be working on my game right now.
结果我现在却在二手车场
Instead, I'm in a used car lot
玩这种恶作剧电话 把生活搞得像个笑话
making a mockery of my life, doing prank calls.
- 你们在干什么? - 嘿 你怎么还没睡?
- What are you guys doing? - Hey. What are you still doing up?
小点声 我爸妈在睡觉
Keep your voice down. My parents are sleeping.
- 我不知道他们回来了 - 我告诉过你他们回来了
- I didn't know they were back. - I told you they were back.
- 我爸的车呢? - 在车库里
- Where's my dad's car? - It's in the garage.
迪昂 我跟你说 我们这一天过得简直难以置信
You're not gonna believe, Dion, when I tell you the day that we had.
- 你骗了我 - 不 我没有 你在说什么呢?
- You tricked me. - No, I didn't. What are you talking about?
- 你确实骗了 你这骗子婊子 - 喔
- Yes, you did, you lying bitch. - Whoa.
嘿 嘴放干净点 你这死肥猪
Hey, you watch your mouth, you fat piece of shit.
- 别这么跟我说话 - 别这么跟他说话
- Don't talk to me like that. - Don't talk to him like that.
他可是我全世界最铁的朋友
He's one of my favorite people on the planet.
- 叫他别这么跟我说话 - 别这么跟她说话
- Tell him not to talk to me like that. - Don't talk to her like that.
- 别这么跟他说话 - 小声点
- Don't talk to him like that. - Keep it down.
是我让她干的 我不开口她肯定不会干
I'm the one that told her to do it. She wouldn't have if I didn't.
- 把车钥匙给我 - 行 就在这儿 拿着
- Give me the car keys. - Okay, they're right here. Okay?
- 咱们出了点小剐蹭... - 什么?
- We got into a little fender bender... - What?
...但没大碍
...but it's gonna be okay.
- 只是点小伤 我会赔的 - 拿什么赔? 什么时候赔?
- It's minor damage. I can pay for it. - How? When?
迪昂 这么晚了 咱们都该歇歇了
Dion, it's very late right now. We should all get a little bit of rest.
明早吃早饭时我会跟你爸解释清楚
I'll smooth it over with your father at breakfast.
- 他不会生气的... - 你们不能住这儿!
- He's not gonna get angry-- - You're not staying here!
- 咱们没别的地方住了 - 你们必须得走
- We got no other place to stay. - You guys gotta go.
不 迪昂 咱们必须得留下
No. Dion. We have to stay.
- 咱们没处去... 迪昂 别赶人 - 不行 嘘
- We have nowhere-- Dion. Stop it. - No. Shh.
她都怀孕八个月了 你疯了吗?
She's eight months pregnant. Are you out of your mind?
- 咱们能不能再谈谈? - 声音小点
- Please can we just talk about it? - Keep your voice down.
深更半夜的 你要把咱们赶到大街上?
Gonna throw us out in the street in the dead of night?
- 没错 走吧 - 咱们真的没地方去
- Yeah, yeah. - We've got nowhere to go.
拿上你们的破烂赶紧滚
Get your shit and leave.
你知道咱们今天经历了什么吗?
Do you have any idea what we've been through today?
我没在跟你说话
I'm not talking to you.
你不想跟我说话?
You're not talking to me?
现在你彻底不打算跟我说话了?
Now you're not talking to me, period?
真离谱
Unbelievable.
含着金汤匙出生肯定很爽吧
Must be nice being born with a silver spoon in your mouth.
而咱们有些人得为了生活奔波
Meanwhile, some of us have to work for a living.
你听过"工作"这词儿吗?
You ever heard that word, "work"?
而不是整天躲屋里涂鸦
Instead of doodling in your room all day?
居然把朋友往大街上赶...
Throwing your friends out on the street...
别一直盯着咱们看行吗? 看墙去
Can you not stare at us? Can you look at the wall?
看得我毛骨悚然
You're creeping me out.
咱们要去哪? 因为...
Where are we gonna go? Because...
- 对不住 既然这儿就有张床... - 没事的
- I'm sorry. You have a bed right here... - It's okay.
- ...我本来能睡上面的 - 没事的
- ...and I could be sleeping on it. - It's okay.
我肚里还有个娃呢 我肚里还有个娃呢
And I got a baby in me. I got a baby in me.
看看你在干嘛?
See what you're doing?
大半夜的把孕妇赶出门
You're throwing a pregnant woman out in the dead of the night.
你会一辈子受良心谴责的
It's gonna live on your conscience forever.
- 你干嘛要这么折磨自己? - 对不起
- Why would you do this to yourself? - I'm sorry.
能让我陪她待一会儿吗? 我得安慰她
Can I have a moment with her, please? Just to comfort her,
跟我亲妹妹单独待会 好吗?
in privacy with my sister, please?
- 让她小声点 - 我尽量 但我得先让她冷静下来
- Keep her voice down. - I'm gonna try, but I gotta calm her down.
抱歉
Sorry.
我不知道该怎么办 我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do. I don't know what to do.
演得真好
That was really good.
- 瑞秋 演得太牛了 - 谢谢
- That was amazing, Rachel. - Thank you.
太到位了 没准能成
That was so good, it might work.
- 如果他把咱们赶走 咱们去哪? - 他现在可能真会留咱们住下
- Where are we gonna go if he kicks us out? - He might actually let us stay now.
那演技简直绝了
That acting was so brilliant.
- 你真的在哭吗? - 没 马蒂 你在干什么?
- Are you actually crying? - No. Marty, what are you doing?
- 那是什么? - 什么?
- What is that? - What?
这是化妆品?
Is this makeup?
等等
Hold on.
等等听我说 听我解释 这不怪我 好吗?
Just wait. Because I can explain. It's not my fault. Okay?
闭嘴
No talking.
- 我也是没法子 你懂吗? - 够了 求你别说了 闭嘴
- I didn't have a choice, you know? - Stop. Stop, please. Stop.
- 瑞秋 别说了 - 我得离开那儿
- Rachel, stop. - I needed to get out.
- 看到我现在有多冷静了吗? 但快到头了 - 对
- See how calm I am? It's not gonna last. - Yeah.
给我滚出去
Get the fuck out of here.
- 不 我觉得... - 给我滚出去
- No. What I think-- - Get the fuck out of here.
- 我觉得咱们都该走 因为... - 闭嘴
- I think that we should both go because... - Stop.
这种破事也就我妈能干得出来
This is the kinda shit my mother would do to me.
亏我这么对你 偏偏是你 居然也这么对我?
How could you of all people do this to me, the way I treat you?
- 我怎么对你了? - 对 明知道我经历了什么还这么干?
- How could I do this to you? - Yes, knowing what I'm going through?
- 那你对我做的这些呢? - 够了 嘘 你在干嘛...
- How about what you're doing to me? - Stop. Shh. What are you doing...
哪怕有一秒钟 你考虑过你正在做什么吗...
Have you ever for one second thought about what you're doing--
- 住口 - 闭上你的臭嘴吧 你这自恋的畜生
- Stop. - Shush yourself, you narcissistic prick.
- 别碰我! - 够了 你们在干什么?
- Don't touch me! - Stop. What are you doing?
- 你要把我爸妈吵醒了 闭嘴 - 去他妈的你父母吧
- You're gonna wake my parents up. Shut up. - Enough about your fucking parents.
你他妈都三十岁的人了 难道不是吗?
Aren't you, like, 30 years old?
你意识到我还有四周就生了吗?
You realize I'm due in four weeks?
- 我还有四周就生了! - 孩子又不是我的
- I am due in four weeks! - It's not my baby.
而且孩子就是他的 顺便说下 真是他妈的孩子
And it's his baby, by the way. It's his fucking baby.
这事儿他也在撒谎
He's lying about that too.
- 我家出什么事了? - 爸 我只是带几个朋友过来
- What's going on in my house? - I was just having some friends over, Dad.
伙计 你还好吗?
Buddy, how are you?
嘿 明早咱们得第一时间和斯伯丁开会
Hey, we have a meeting with Spalding first thing in the morning
- 为了"至尊"的样球 - 迪昂 算了吧 别演了
- for the Supreme samples. - Dion, come on. Give me a break.
那根本就不可能成
That's never gonna happen.
- 你拿了我儿子的钱 - 您在说什么呢?
- You've taken my son's money. - What are you talking about?
我不信 迪 难道你看不出来发生了什么吗?
I don't believe it. D, don't you see what's happening?
- 简直离谱 太他妈离谱了... - 你一直都在骗我儿子
- Unbelievable. Un-fucking... - You're conning my son all along.
- 我才没有骗你儿子 - 你卷走了他所有的钱
- I am not conning your son. - You're taking all his money.
我给了他生活的意义 哪怕你只给了他钱
I give him meaning. All you do is give him money.
- 我给了他奋斗的目标 - 给我听好!
- I give him purpose. - You listen to me!
他他妈看都不敢看你一眼 他怕你怕得要死
He won't even fucking look at you, he's so petrified of you.
咱们怎么办 哈? 你们打算让咱们去哪儿?
What are we gonna do, huh? Where do you expect us to go?
你真想让我睡大街? 我怀孕了
You really want me to sleep on the street? I'm pregnant.
别 别 迪昂! 迪昂!
No, no, no. Dion! Dion!
行吧 瑞秋 我得告诉你件事 我没想针对你
All right, I gotta tell you something, Rachel. It's not intended to be mean.
我有我的使命 而你没有
I have a purpose. You don't.
如果你觉得那算是什么恩赐 那你就大错特错了
If you think that's some sort of blessing, it's not.
那反倒成了我人生中巨大的劣势
It puts me at a huge life disadvantage.
它意味着我背负着要成就某件事的义务
It means I have an obligation to see a very specific thing through.
而那份义务必然伴随着牺牲 懂吗?
And with that obligation comes sacrifice, okay?
我的人生是我所有被迫做出的选择的产物
My life is the product of all the choices I've had to make.
而你的人生则是...
Your life is the product of...
我都不知道你的人生算什么产物
I don't even know what your life is the product of.
你过一天算一天 你这种人就这样
You're making it up as you go. That's the kind of person you are.
我可不是那种人 懂吗?
That's not the kind of person I am, okay?
你得为你那些操蛋决定负责
You're responsible for the shitty decisions you've made.
我从没叫你结婚 一次都没有
I never told you to get married, not once.
- 你别想把这些赖在我头上 - 我明白
- You cannot pawn them off onto me. - I understand.
你在宠物店一年挣多少?
How much do you make a year at the pet store?
差不多1200块
About $1200.
听着 免得你忘了 我得在一周内弄到1500块
Okay, in case you forgot, I have a week to make $1500,
还没算机票呢
not including air fare.
我现在得专注 别让我分心
I need to focus right now, no distractions.
- 真的很抱歉 - 没事
- I'm really sorry. - No, it's okay.
显而易见 我现在没法安定下来
It goes without saying, I'm in no position to settle down right now.
断了这个念头吧 我现在不会安定下来的 好吗?
Get that out of your mind. I will not settle down right now. Okay?
要是你真打算离开艾拉 我不会抛弃你的
If you're serious about leaving Ira, I will not abandon you.
作为朋友 我会帮你
As your friend, I will help you.
咱们会去查 找个好的待产院
We'll do the research, we'll find a great maternity home.
他们会收留你 给孩子找个好人家
They'll take you in, they'll ensure the baby's got a good family.
我们可以办个... 不行? 怎么了?
We could do a-- No? No?
那就回家吧 瑞秋 回家去
Then go home, Rachel. Just go home.
- 我该怎么说? - 你会想出办法的 回家吧 瑞秋
- What am I gonna say? - You'll figure it out. Go home, Rachel.
艾拉 醒醒
Ira, wake up.
孩子不是你的
It's not your baby.
蠢货 给我看着地
Stupid bitch, look at the fucking ground,
活脱脱一个臭婊子
like a dumb fucking whore.
操
Fuck.
真是他妈的扯淡 给我滚那边去
Fucking bullshit. Fucking go over there.
给他妈我站到墙角去
Stand in the fucking corner.
我要抽死你... 你想找死吗?
I'm gonna smack... You wanna do this?
那野种肯定跟它那死爹一样 是个满脸脓包的废物
That baby's gonna be a pimple-faced bum just like its fucking father.
或者是像它那臭婊子妈一样的贱货
Or it's gonna be a whore like its fucking whore mother.
现在就开门! 别人还要睡觉呢!
Open up the door right now! There are people trying to sleep!
什么?
What?
- 住手! 安静! - 嘿 瑞秋 你新婆婆来了
- Stop this! Quiet! - Hey, Rachel. It's your new mother-in-law.
- 艾拉! 别这么跟她说! 对不起 - 嘿 恭喜啊 毛瑟太太
- Ira! Don't say that to her! I'm sorry. - Hey, congratulations, Mrs. Mauser.
- 您要当祖母了 - 什么?
- You're gonna be a grandmother. - What?
行了 瑞秋现在是你的累赘了 拿着她的破烂
Here, she's your problem now. Here, take her shit.
瑞秋 你需要帮忙吗?
Rachel, do you need help?
- 够了 抱歉 - 亲爱的 需不需要帮忙?
- That's enough. I'm sorry. - Do you need help, honey?
- 没 我没事 大家回去睡吧 - 呵 很好 她倒挺愧疚的
- No, I'm okay. Everyone, go back to bed. - Yeah, great. She's so sorry.
- 你是瑞秋? - 你是埃兹拉?
- Are you Rachel? - You're Ezra?
- 他在哪? - 给钱我就带他出来
- Where is he? - Give me the money and I'll bring him out.
给钱? 不见到我的狗 你一分钱也别想拿
Money? You ain't getting a nickel unless I see my dog.
告诉你 我可不是一个人 懂吗? 到处都是我的人盯着呢
Just so you know, I'm not alone, okay? I got people watching all around me.
我他妈才不管谁盯着
I don't give a shit who's watching.
我是说我有的是底气 劝你别耍花样
I'm letting you know I'm very protected right now in case you try anything.
- 什么? - 行了 你到底要不要你的狗?
- What? - Okay, do you want your dog?
狗就在我这儿
I have your dog.
- 你干嘛? - 我不要那个项圈
- What are you doing? - I don't want that collar.
- 我要项圈里的东西 - 拿钱出来
- I want what's inside the collar. - Show me the money.
如果我没弄到你的狗 我会有这个吗? 不可能
Would I have this if I didn't have your dog? No.
所以把钱拿出来 我这就去把他牵给你
So show me the money, and I'll go and get him for you.
快点 赶紧的!
Come on. Come on!
妹子 你不知道你在跟谁玩呢 懂吗?
You don't know who you're playing with, girl. Okay?
- 钱在这儿 - 我他妈才不管
- Here's the money. - I don't fucking care.
让我看看信封里装了什么
Show me what's inside the envelope.
我怎么知道里面到底有没有货?
How am I supposed to know there's anything in there?
- 瞧 想看是吧? 给你看 行了吧? - 行 太好了
- Here, you wanna see? Here, look. Okay? - Yes. Great.
- 你去哪 妹子? - 她到底有没有带狗?
- Where you going, girl? - Does she have the dog or what?
谁他妈知道
Who the fuck knows?
好
Okay.
- 喂 布拉尼石酒吧 - 嗨 是我
- Yeah, Blarney Stone.- Hi, it's me.
“是我”是谁?
Who's "me"?
好的 谢谢 可以把狗牵出来了
Yeah, thank you. You can bring the dog out now.
你就是那个丢下狗的人? 说好的“马上回来”呢?
You're the one that left the dog? What happened to "coming right back"?
我们准备好了 牵出来吧
We're ready, so you can walk him outside.
- 那畜生尿了一地 - 好的 待会儿见
- The thing's pissed all over the floor.- Okay. I'll see you soon.
- 怎么回事? - 听我说一下 好吗?
- What is going on? - Listen to me for a second, okay?
看 那边 瞧见没?
Look. Right over there. Okay?
那个绿顶篷
The green awning.
我朋友马上会牵着狗出来
My friend's gonna come out in a second with the dog.
只要你给钱 我就打电话说账结清了 行吗?
Once you give me the money, I'm gonna call and say we're squared up, okay?
瞧 他正牵着狗呢 没骗你吧
Look, there he is right now with the dog. I told you.
把钱给我吧
So hand me the money.
去你的
Fuck you.
嘿! 嘿 把钱给我
Hey! Hey, give me my money.
那什么... 嘿!
What about... Hey!
抓小偷! 拦住那两个人
Thief! Stop those two.
- 他们抢了我的钱包 - 嘿
- They took my wallet. - Hey.
拦住他们!
Stop them!
往哪跑? 嘿
Where you going? Hey.
- 撒手 - 赶紧的
- Get off of me. - Come on.
嘿 还有那个! 那个打石膏的!
Hey, him too! Him with the cast!
那个打石膏的
With the cast.
你们居然想抢孕妇的东西?
What are you doing trying to steal from a pregnant woman?
- 妈的 - 嘿 警察!
- Shit. - Hey, police!
这他妈是什么 伙计?
What the fuck is this, man?
那不是摩西 嘿
That not Moses. Hey.
那不是我的狗
That's not my dog.
喂 我在这儿 那个女的叫我过来的
Yo, I'm out here. The lady said to come here.
- 他妈的耍我是吧? - 离远点 嘿!
- Fucking playing games with me? - Stay away. Hey!
他妈的耍我是吧? 哈?
Fucking playing games with me? Huh?
你他妈跟我玩什么花招呢?
What kind of fucking shit you playing with me?
- 嘿 给我死开 退后 伙计 - 嘿 冷静点 妈的
- Hey, get the fuck off me. Back up, man. - Hey, calm down. Shit.
- 妈的 - 站住
- Shit. - Stop there.
谁来帮帮她!
Someone help her!
- 救命! 帮帮我! - 被我逮到了吧 你这臭婊子!
- Somebody! Help! - I got you, you fucking bitch!
嘿! 住手!
Hey! Stop!
怎么了?
What is it?
- 嘿 别来无恙? - 你在这儿干什么?
- Hey, how are you doing? - What are you doing here?
都十二点半了 我在想你愿不愿意一块儿吃午饭
It's 12:30. I was wondering if you wanted to get lunch.
想都别想 我今晚演出首映
It's out of the question. I have a show opening tonight.
- 耽搁你一小时行吗? - 不行
- Well, can I steal you away for an hour? - No.
- 能跟你谈谈吗? 拜托 - 我很忙
- Can I talk to you for a second? Please. - I'm very busy.
就一分钟 拜托了
Please, it'll just take a second.
额...
Um...
- 跟你说这事我还有点紧张 - 什么事?
- I feel kind of nervous telling you this. - What?
好吧 呃 这东西是我从你那儿偷的 行吗?
All right, uh, I stole this from you, okay?
我想把它还给你 明白吗?
And I want to return it. All right?
对不起 我本打算把它卖了再也不见你
I'm sorry. My plan was to sell it and never see you again.
可我总是忍不住想起你 我没法偷你的东西
But I can't stop thinking about you, and I can't steal from you.
嗯
Mmm.
你知道那是廉价首饰 对吧?
You know that's costume jewelry, right?
- 这是假货? 我真是个蠢货 - 剧组道具
- This is costume jewelry? I'm an idiot. - From the production.
你那套全靠自己的志气呢? 之前的慷慨陈词上哪去了?
What happened to doing it all on your own? Where did that speech go?
我知道 我满嘴喷粪 行了吧?
I know, I'm completely full of shit, okay?
我当时手头紧 缺钱才偷了你的东西
I was in a tight spot, and I stole from you cause I needed some money,
我做错了
and it was wrong.
我破产了
I'm broke.
听着 我一点门路都没有
Look, I got no resources.
下周日本有锦标赛 我连去的路费都没有
I got the championship next week in Japan. I got no way to get there.
我没招了 没人能帮我 凯
I got no options. I got no one looking out for me, Kay.
当然 这不是你的麻烦 所以我才来归还 懂吗?
Which isn't your problem. Which is why I'm returning it, okay?
- 知道我怎么想吗? - 什么?
- You know what I think? - What?
我觉得你是去销赃才发现那是垃圾
I think you went to sell that and discovered it was junk.
没有
No.
现在你带着这种荒唐的套路出现
And now you've shown up here with this ridiculous strategy
就为了博取同情让我掏钱
to get me to have some sympathy and open my wallet.
太荒唐了 你觉得我会这样侮辱你的智商吗?
That's absurd. You think I would insult your intelligence like that?
- 你还要演下去? - 演什么?
- Are you gonna keep going? - Keep going what?
- 你还要继续玩这套? - 我只是在做自己
- Are you gonna keep on with this? - Just being myself.
- 你满嘴谎话 - 我没有 这就是真实的我
- You're lying through your teeth. - I'm not. It's me being me.
- 真可悲 你在做自己? - 我说的是真话
- This is pathetic. You're being you? - I am telling you the truth.
我偷了你的东西然后感到内疚
I stole from you and then I feel bad about it,
- 所以想来补救 - 别白费劲了 我不在乎
- so I'm trying to make amends. - You're wasting your energy. I don't care.
换了我也会偷我自己的
I would have stolen from me too.
凯
Kay.
- 嗨 - 看来我打断你们了
- Hi. - Looks like I'm interrupting something.
不 不 没那回事
No, no. Not at all.
这位是马丁 我朋友卡罗尔的儿子 他正要走
This is Martin, my friend Carol's son. He was just leaving.
- 这位是默尔 我的公关 - 你好
- This is Merle, my publicist. - Hello.
马丁想当个演员 但可惜他演技不太行
Martin would like to be an actor, but unfortunately he's not very good.
额 那个
Ah, well, you know,
- 百老汇也需要领位员嘛 - 座位安排得怎么样了?
- Broadway needs ushers too. - So what's happening with the seating?
我跟米尔顿谈过了 他会派所有员工过来
I spoke to Milton. He's sending all of his employees.
就像强制任务 公司的内部指标
It's like a mandate. Like, a company mandate.
这就能让我高兴了?
This is supposed to make me happy?
我是说 既然座无虚席 目的不就达到了吗?
Well, I mean, it's a full house. Isn't that the point?
满座的他妈的蠢货 - 不 没那么糟 里面还有点--
Full of fucking morons. - No, no. You got some--
- 弗雷德·阿斯泰尔要来 - 好 我不在这儿碍事了
- Fred Astaire is coming. - Okay, I'm gonna get out your hair...
别 一定要给他一张今晚的票
No. Make sure you give him a ticket for tonight.
- 真的? - 是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
噢 小伙子 你这下有福了
Oh. You are in for such a treat, young man.
当你看到这位女士演戏时
When you see this lady act,
你会觉得就像被吸尘器口爆了一样
you're gonna feel like you got your cock sucked by a vacuum cleaner.
- 默尔! - 她脸红了 看见没?
- Merle! - She's blushing. See her?
什么?
What?
坐回你那臭位子上
Take your stinking seat.
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
你他妈疯了吗?
Have you lost your damned mind?
杰德 我在跟你说话
Jed. I'm talking to you.
我只是在练准头 妈
I was just practicing my aim, Mama.
你总说做人要有大志向
You always said to shoot for the stars.
嘿
Hey.
过来
Come.
抱歉迟到了 脱不开身
I'm sorry I'm late. I couldn't get away.
- 呵 我信 - 他一直缠着我
- Oh, I bet. - He was all over me.
你今晚棒极了 简直不可思议
You were incredible tonight. That was unbelievable.
- 我有东西送你 - 给我的?
- I have something for you. - For me?
转过去
Turn around.
每年结婚纪念日我丈夫都会送我一件珠宝
Every year my husband gives me a piece of jewelry for our anniversary.
我有25件了 每一件都代表一年的痛苦
I have 25 of them. One for each year of misery.
这够你那趟路费了 没准还有剩
That should cover your trip and then some.
戴着这玩意儿让我觉得反胃
Wearing it makes me feel like shit.
噢 操 停下 停下 停下
Oh, shit. Stop, stop, stop.
停
Stop.
嘿! 嘿 你们在干什么?
Hey! Hey, what are you doing?
- 该死 天哪 - 站起来!
- Shit. Oh, God. - Get up!
- 别乱动 - 站起来 我看见你了
- Lay still. - Stand up, I see you.
听我口令就跑 一 二 三 起
When I tell you, run. One, two, three. Get up.
- 快点 跑 - 嘿!
- Come on. Go. - Hey!
乔伊 拦住他们!
Joey, stop them!
快点 快点 快点
Come on. Come on. Come on.
嘿 嘿 你们去哪? 跑这儿干嘛呢?
Hey. Hey. Where are you guys going? What are you guys doing here?
- 没干嘛 - 不 不 不
- Nothing. - No, no, no.
- 让我看到你们的双手 - 铐上他
- Let me see both of your hands. - Cuff him.
- 噢 天哪 我们只是... - 我们什么都没干
- Oh, my God. We were just... - We didn't do anything.
饶了我们吧 我们在草地里找她的耳环
Give us a break. We were looking for her earrings in the grass.
我的耳环掉了 我们在找我的耳环
My earring came off. We were looking for my earring.
瞧你耳朵上不是挂着两只吗
It looks like you've got two earrings in your ears there.
不是这只 是... 之前的 还有一只
Not this earring. There was... From before. There was another earring.
今天早些时候还有另一对耳环
There's another pair of earrings from earlier in the day.
我认得你
I recognize you.
- 噢 天哪 - 你是凯·斯通
- Oh, God. Oh, God. - You're Kay Stone.
- 没错 我太清楚你是谁了 - 见鬼了
- Yes. I know exactly who you are. - This is not happening.
- 让我看到你的手 - 你认真的吗?
- Let see your hands. - Are you serious?
这样吧 我回家取个钱包
You know, I will go home,
拿点现金给你们 毕竟给你们添麻烦了
and I'll get my wallet, and I will get you some cash because we've put you out.
- 拜托 长官 她这就回家拿钱包 给你现金
- Please, officer. She's gonna go home and get her wallet. And give you cash.
- 有证件吗? - 没 没证件
- Got ID? - No. No ID.
- 铐上她 - 别 拜托
- Cuff her. - No, please.
- 没证件是吧? 让我搜搜 - 拜托了 别这样
- No ID, huh? Let's see. - Please, please. No, no, no.
- 拜托 让我回家行吗? - 少废话
- Please, will you just let me go home? - Come on.
我向你保证
I'll give you my word.
哇 瞧瞧 真是条漂亮的项链
Wow, lookie here. That's a really nice necklace.
拿去 拿去吧 归你了
Take it. Take it. It's yours.
太感谢了
Thank you very much.
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
你能再帮我弄条项链吗?
Do you think you could grab me another necklace?
你认真的吗?
Are you serious?
你说这些对你没意义 就几分钟的事
You said them mean nothing to you. It'd just take you a couple of minutes.
我才刚消失了半小时 不能上去又马上下来
I was just gone for half an hour. I can't go up and come right back down.
- 我妈在那呢 - 你刚才给警察倒是挺爽快
- My mother is up there. - You'd do that for the police officers.
- 噢天呐 我的头发 - 我在走廊等
- Oh, my God. My hair. - I'll wait in the hall.
不 准跟着
No, you will not.
等等 等等
Wait. Wait.
好了
There.
你真美
You look beautiful.
拜托 你有25条呢
Please, you have 25 of them.
行了!
Fine!
- 待这儿 明白吗? - 我在这待着 好吧
- Stay here. Do you understand me? - I'll stay here. Okay.
- 别乱动 - 好的
- Do not move. - Okay.
妈的
Shit.
你好 很高兴见到你们
Hello. Lovely to see you.
- 大卫 你好吗? - 挺好 你呢?
- David, how are you? - Good. How are you?
你他妈死哪去了?
Where the fuck have you been?
我想清静一会儿 有问题吗?
I needed a moment to myself. Is that a problem?
我不知道出门还得请示
I didn't realize I needed a permission slip.
我为你操办了这一切 你却让我像个蠢货
I put this whole thing on for you and you're making me look like an idiot.
天哪
God.
听着 默尔正跟《纽约时报》通电话
Look. Merle's on the phone right now with The New York Times.
什么?
What?
他找了个排版员正读剧评呢
He's got a printer who's gonna read the review.
我的天
My God.
- 还是说你压根不在乎? - 接通了! 接通了!
- Or do you not care? - I got him! I have him!
- 噢天呐 来了 - 快来 快来!
- Oh, my God. Okay. - Come, come, come!
来了!
Coming!
- 快点 拿到剧评了! - 来了
- Hurry, he has the review! - I'm coming.
剧评!
The review!
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
- 快来 - 来了
- Come on, come on. - Okay.
拉乌尔 凯
Raoul, Kay.
好了 标题 "凯·斯通回归" 作者罗伯特...
Okay. Title, "Kay Stone Returns" by Robert...
- 祝今晚愉快 - 门开着 大家都要下来了
- Have a good night. - Leave it open. Everyone's coming down.
- 是吗? - 是啊
- Are they? - Oh, yeah.
派对结束了
Party's over.
晚安
Good night.
派对结束了
The party's over.
- 他们在赶咱们走 - 什么意思? 咱们才刚到
- They're asking us to leave. - What do you mean? We just got here.
他们该在门口拦住咱们的 凭什么让咱们进来?
They should've stopped us at the door. Why'd they let us in?
打扰下 你知道凯在哪儿吗?
Excuse me. Do you know where Kay is?
- 她在楼上卧室 - 好的
- She's upstairs in her bedroom. - Okay.
嗨 凯在里面吗?
Hi. Is Kay in there?
现在不方便
This is not a good time.
好的 但我能跟她谈谈吗?
Okay, but can I just speak to her?
我说了 现在真的不方便
As I said, it's really not a good time.
到年底 如果这人帮你挣了钱 你就留着他
At the end of the year, if the guy made you money, you keep him.
否则你就让他滚蛋
And if not, you throw the bum out.
打扰下
Excuse me.
- 嗨 - 你在开玩笑吧
- Hi. - You gotta be kidding me.
- 抱歉上门打扰 - 你是怎么进我家的?
- I'm sorry to disturb you in your home. - How did you get in my house?
请再给我一次机会 我都给你跪下了
Please give me another chance. I am on my hands and knees.
我得去日本 还需要1500块参加锦标赛
I need a ride to Japan and I need $1,500 so I can compete in the championship.
我非常 非常需要这份工作
I need this job very, very badly.
我求你了
I'm begging you.
我随你怎么使唤 故意输球也行
I'll work for you however you want. I will lose.
除了让你的活动圆满成功 我没任何个人立场
I'll have no personal point of view apart from making your event a success.
马蒂 人生没有第二次机会
Marty, there are no second chances in life.
- 凭什么没有? - 我给过你工作 你拒绝了!
- Why not? - I offered you the job and you said no!
我知道 那是因为我冲动 我后悔了
I know, because I was impulsive. And I regret it.
然后呢?
And?
然后就是我太无礼 太自负了
And I was rude and overconfident.
我太狂妄了 态度也有问题
And I was cocky, and I copped an attitude.
还有呢?
And?
绝不会有下次了 对不起
And it won't happen again. I'm sorry.
请再给我一次机会 洛克威尔先生
Please just give me another chance, Mr. Rockwell.
我任凭你发落 让我做什么都行
I'm throwing myself at your mercy. I'll do whatever you want.
你们怎么看? 我该给这小混蛋第二次机会吗?
What do you guys think? Should I give this little asshole a second chance?
- 拜托 给吧! - 别问我
- Yes, please! - Don't ask me.
你不知道这对我有多重要 拜托 我求你了
You don't know how important this is to me. Please. I'm begging you.
就让我搭你的飞机 让我跟你们一起去
Just let me go on your plane, and let me join you there.
拜托 我是在低声下气地求你
Please, I'm humbling myself before you.
- 看着你就反胃 - 对不起
- You're making me sick. - I'm sorry.
- 站起来! - 好的 行
- Stand up! - Okay. All right.
拜托 好吗? 我什么都肯做
Please. Okay? I'll do anything.
- 什么都肯做? - 是的 任何事
- Anything? - Yes. Anything.
行吧
Okay.
顺着走廊走 右手边第二扇门是我办公室
Go down the hall. Second door on the right is my office.
去把球拍拿来
Grab the paddle and bring it back here.
这比戏里演得还带劲
This is more dramatic than the play.
- 好的 - 确实
- Okay. - That's true.
噢 马蒂 把球拍给我
Oh, Marty. Give me the paddle.
听好了 我要你这么做
So here's what I want you to do.
我要你趴在椅子上 把裤子脱了
I want you to bend over that chair and drop your pants.
你认真的?
Are you for real?
你真是个淘气坏小子 现在该打屁股了
You've been a really bad boy. Now you're gonna get a spanking.
别这样 你认真的吗?
Come on. Are you serious?
你想去日本的 对吧?
You wanna get to Japan, don't you?
是的 我想去日本 但这就是你想要的?
Yeah, I wanna go to Japan. But this is what you want?
必须得这么干 趴好
That's what it's gonna take. Now bend over.
好吧 说清楚
Okay, so to be clear,
你带我去日本 然后再给我报酬?
you're gonna bring me to Japan and then you're gonna compensate me?
明早八点半 拉瓜迪亚机场 咱们出发去日本
Tomorrow morning, 8:30, LaGuardia. We're on our way to Japan.
- 我需要票吗? - 飞机是我的
- Do I need a ticket? - I own the plane.
我怎么知道你会说话算数?
How do I know you're gonna honor this?
你不知道 因为你没资格讨价还价
You don't. Because you have no power here.
趴好
Now bend over.
手放这儿 弧度要漂亮点
Put your hands over here. I want a nice arc.
开始吧
Let's go.
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
行了 我准备好了
Okay, I'm ready.
这一下是替我儿子打的
This one is for my son.
好
Okay.
这一下是为我自己
This one is for me.
该死!
God!
现在是加分环节
Now the bonus round.
漂亮的球拍 一面是木头 一面是海绵
Beautiful paddle. One side's wood and the other is foam.
- 嘿 马蒂 怎么样? - 嘿 泰德 嘿 劳伦斯
- Hey, Marty, how you doin'? - Hey, Ted. Hey, Lawrence.
噢 妈的 嘿 伙计 近来可好?
Aw, damn. Hey, man. How you doin'?
你看我今晚能住后屋吗?
You think I could stay in the back room tonight?
哇 伙计 布莱恩今晚住那儿
Wow, man. I got Brian staying there tonight.
我本想让你住家里的 但我老婆不答应
I would let you stay at the house, man, but the wife ain't havin' it.
我就在这儿晃悠到起飞吧
I'm just gonna hang around until my flight.
你要去哪?
Where you goin'?
去日本 明早八点出发
Going to Japan. Tomorrow morning, 8:00 a.m.
- 噢耶! - 好样的小伙子!
- Oh, yeah! - My man!
- 哟 你真要去啦! 弄到钱了 - 是啊 是啊
- Yo, you goin'! You got that money. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
真为你高兴 伙计
Good for you, man.
你看着一点都不兴奋啊
You ain't even look like you excited.
没 我... 我挺好的 我挺好
No, I'm-- I'm good. I'm good.
知道你那哥们沃利在后头吧 他一直在等你
You know your boy back there, Wally, he's been waitin' on you.
- 沃利在这儿? - 沃利 对
- Wally's here? - Wally, yeah.
- 他怎么样? - 沃利挺好 挺淡定的 伙计
- How'd he seem? - Wally's good. He cool, man.
他就在后头哪待着呢
He's back there somewhere.
他看好你 他出一块 她出一块
He believes in you. He has a dollar. She has a dollar.
嘿 怎么样?
Hey. How you doing?
噢 哇! 见到你真高兴! 怎么样?
Oh, wow! How you doing? Nice to see you!
我一直想联系你
I've been trying to get in touch with you.
- 噢 真的? - 是啊 你的狗呢? 摩西怎么样了?
- Oh, really? - Yeah. How's your dog? How's Moses doing?
你能别废话了吗?
You wanna cut the bullshit?
没废话 我是真的关心他
No bullshit. I'm genuinely concerned about him.
- 马蒂 你没事吧 伙计? - 没事 我挺好
- Marty. You good, man? - Yeah, I'm good.
现在 听我说 听着 听着 听着
Now, listen to me. Listen. Listen. Listen.
你那小妞就在楼下车里 她正等你呢
I got your girl downstairs in the car. She's waiting for you.
你他妈在说什么? 瑞秋在你那儿?
What the fuck are you telling me? You got Rachel?
对
Yeah.
她跟我说我的狗在新泽西某处 而且你有地址
She told me my dog's in Jersey somewhere. And you got the address.
- 好的 - 咱们走
- Okay. - Let's go.
行吧 好吧 让我...
Okay. All right. Let me, uh...
额 行吧 让我先...
Um, okay, let me just...
给我两秒钟 我就跟我哥们说句话
Give me two seconds. I just wanna say one thing to my friend.
给你两秒钟行 但老子可不等你
Give you two seconds, yeah, but I'm not gonna be here.
- 你要去哪? - 我去哪?
- Where you gonna be? - Where am I gonna be?
我这就下楼拿榔头砸你那小妞的肚子
I'm gonna be downstairs taking a hammer to your girl's stomach.
这就是我要干的事
That's where I'm gonna be.
行了 知道了 知道了
Okay. All right. All right.
喂 毛瑟!
Yo, Mouse!
- 搞快点 走 - 好吧
- Come on. Let's go. - Okay.
父母留给咱们的钱 他的那份大半都被我拿了
Well, I took most of his share of the money that our parents left us.
- 你花了你弟的钱? - 是的
- You spent your brother's money? - Yes, I did.
呵 看来你挺疼你弟的?
Yeah, you love your brother?
也许你能给我弟安排个差事 你知道他是个讲究人
Maybe you could give my brother a job. You know he's a good man.
我把你的差事给他 行了吧? 米奇 帮个忙
I'll give him your job, okay? Mitch, do me a favor.
干嘛?
What?
闭嘴 行吗?
Stop talking. Okay?
好了 看到那边的加油站了吗?
Okay. See the gas station there?
左手边那栋房子就是
it's the house to the left.
- 下个左转口? - 对
- Next left? - Yeah.
知道了
I got it.
下车 赶紧的
Get out of the car. Come on.
米奇 过来
Mitch, come.
- 鲁本 你看着她 - 噢 好的
- Reuben, you wait with her. - Oh, okay.
老实坐着
Sit tight.
搞快点 使劲敲
Come on. Louder.
敲响点
Knock louder.
那是我的狗
That's my dog.
摩西! 喂!
Moses! Yo!
开门!
Open up!
操 摩西
Fuck. Moses.
- 搞快点 - 我讨厌那只他妈的杂种狗
- Come on. - I hate that fuckin' mutt.
摩西!
Moses!
那是我的狗 摩西!
That's my dog. Moses!
摩西!
Moses!
瞧见里头有什么没?
See anything in there?
没 啥也没瞧见
No, not really.
- 马蒂! - 妈的
- Marty! - Shit.
马蒂! 快跑!
Marty! Go!
马蒂!
Marty!
趴下! 趴下!
Get down! Get down!
操!
Fuck!
马蒂! 马蒂! 我中弹了!
Marty! Marty! I got shot!
救命!
Help!
救命 马蒂! 求你帮帮我!
Help, Marty! Please help!
救命!
Help!
你没事吧? 噢不! 你还好吗?
Are you okay? Oh, no! Are you okay?
- 你还好吗? - 这他妈是怎么回事?
- Are you okay? - What the fuck's going on?
好了 没事的
Okay. It's okay.
我流血了 我在流血
I'm bleeding, I'm bleeding.
好了 没事了 没事了 没事了
Okay. It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
- 真的很抱歉 - 对不起
- I'm so sorry. - I'm sorry.
- 快去拿钱 - 什么钱?
- Go get the money. - What money?
快去拿钱 就在他口袋里 在他兜里
Go get the money. It's in his pocket. It's in his pocket.
你确定?
Are you sure?
- 钱! 就在内兜里! - 好的 知道了 知道了
- The money! It's in the inside pocket! - Okay, okay, okay.
噢 操
Oh, fuck.
这什么玩意?
What is this?
噢 你这混蛋...
Oh, you motherfucker...
好了 好了 没事了 没事了
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
怎么回事? 操!
What happened? Fuck!
撒开我! 你想上哪儿去?
Get off me! Where do you think you're going?
没事的
it's okay.
行了
Okay.
- 拿到了吗? 拿到了吗? - 嗯 拿到了 拿到了
- You got it? You got it? - Yeah. I got it, I got it.
钱到手了吗?
You got the money?
- 钱多吗? - 挺多的
- Is there a lot of money? - There's a lot.
- 你现在能走了 - 我知道 你表现得太牛了
- You can go now. - I know. You did amazing.
- 你现在可以去参赛了 - 我就知道你行 太棒了
- You can go on your trip now. - I knew you could do this. So good.
你干得太漂亮了
You did such a good job.
我爱你
I love you.
- 亲爱的 你的预产期是什么时候? - 怎么了? 孩子没事吧?
- Honey, when is your due date? - Why? Is the baby okay?
孩子没大碍 我只需要你冷静点
The baby is fine. I just need you to calm down.
- 你是她丈夫吗? - 不是 我是她朋友
- Are you the husband? - No. I'm her friend.
她还有四周就生了 孩子会没事吗?
She's due in four weeks. The baby will be okay?
孩子很安全 现在得说再见了
The baby is okay. It's time to say goodbye.
- 我不能进去? - 手术室只准家属进
- I can't go? - Only family in the operating room.
不 别别别别别!
No, no, no, no, no!
会没事的 瑞秋 没事的 真的没事的
it's gonna be fine. Rachel, it's fine. It's fine.
不 别别别! 马蒂 不要
No, no, no! Marty, no.
他就在门外候着
He'll be right outside.
马蒂 不要!
Marty, no!
瑞秋 我进不去 他们说我不能进去
Rachel, I can't go. They're telling me I can't go.
- 我不想让你... - 请冷静下来
- I don't want you to-- - Please calm down.
- 别走 求你了! - 请冷静点
- Don't go, please! - Please calm down.
求你别走! 马蒂!
Please don't go! Marty!
不!
No!
多谢 欢迎来到日本 洛克威尔先生
Thank you very much. Welcome to Japan, Mr. Rockwell.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
毛瑟先生 毛瑟先生
Mr. Mauser. Mr. Mauser.
噢 洛克威尔先生说让你去队尾
Ah. Mr. Rockwell says the back of the line.
他还不想正式开始
He doesn't want to begin yet.
该练练了 也该整口啤酒了
Needs some practice. Needs a beer.
赛斯先生? 赛斯先生
Mr. Sethi? Mr. Sethi.
嘿 是我 我是马蒂·毛瑟
Hey. It's me. It's Marty Mauser.
怎么样? 实际上 看到你在这儿我挺惊讶的
How you doing? I'm surprised to see you here, actually.
- 怎么说? - 我不知道 我...
- Why's that? - I don't know. I--
咱们确实得宣传锦标赛
We do have a tournament to promote.
嗯 当然 当然
No, of course, of course.
是啊
Yeah.
我想我该为在伦敦时的表现向你道歉
I think I owe you an apology for the way I acted in London.
我当时就是个混账
I was a jackass.
讲礼貌是基本准则 毛瑟先生
There is such a thing as a code of courtesy, Mr. Mauser.
不 我知道 只是...
No, I know. It's just--
在我长大的地方 每个人都只顾自己
It's every man for himself where I come from.
我就是在那样的环境下长大的 懂吗?
That's just how I grew up. Okay?
有时候我觉得自己甚至无法控制...
And sometimes I feel like I don't even have control--
我对你的借口真的没兴趣
I'm really not interested in your excuses.
不 不 知道 这不是借口
No, no, I know. It's not an excuse.
听着 重点是接下来的态度我会好得多
Look, the point is I'm gonna proceed with a much better attitude.
顺便说下 要是今天看到我在场上很无礼
And by the way, if you see me acting rude up there today,
那是人设 是按剧本演的 我会输个14比21
that's a character. This is scripted. I'm gonna lose 21-14.
这不是玩真的 真正的我 那个讲礼貌的我 下周你就能见识到了
This isn't a real thing. The real me, the polite me, you'll see next week.
- 下周? - 锦标赛上
- Next week? - At the championship.
你不参加锦标赛
You're not playing in the championship.
- 什么? - 你今年没资格参赛
- What? - You're not participating this year.
不 不 不 我想你搞错了
No, no, no. I think you're confused.
我参加这活动就是为了这事儿 这样我才能付清剩下的罚款
That's what I'm doing the event for, so I can pay off the rest of my fine.
马上跟我去见洛克威尔先生
Come talk to Mr. Rockwell right now.
锦标赛还有不到两周就开始了
The tournament is less than two weeks away.
- 分组已经定好了 - 不 咱们可以重排分组
- All the bracketing has been set. - No, but we'll redo the bracketing.
我不会为一个自以为是的美国人就打乱整个赛程
I'm not gonna tear up the entire schedule on behalf of one entitled American.
不 赛斯先生 赛斯先生 听着...
No, Mr. Sethi. Mr. Sethi. Look...
我人都在这儿了
I'm here.
我想你不知道我来这儿费了多大劲
I don't think you know how difficult that was, for me to come here.
我现在可是在日本
I'm in Japan right now.
恐怕你走得还不够远
You haven't come far enough, I'm afraid.
什么?
What?
你来这儿纯属白费劲
You have wasted your time coming here.
简直不敢相信
Unbelievable.
我远渡重洋来到日本
I've traveled many miles here to Japan
就是为了挑战我的宿敌 远藤!
to challenge my great nemesis, Endo!
他说什么?
What's he say?
他不想让你再丢人现眼了
He doesn't want to embarrass you anymore.
让我丢脸? 我早就没脸没皮了
Embarrass me? I am beyond embarrassment.
告诉他他是个... 你们的冠军就是个骗子和怂包
Tell him he's a-- Your champion is a fraud and a chicken.
他就是个怂包!
He's chicken!
远藤先生同意比试
Mr. Endo agrees to the match.
挺好
Great.
条件是...
On the condition that...
输家必须当着所有观众的面亲吻一头猪
the loser has to kiss a pig in front of the entire audience.
- 亲猪? - 是的
- A pig? - Yes.
亲猪? 什么?
A pig? What?
他说既然你要表现得像头猪
He said if you are going to act like a pig,
他很乐意帮你配个种
he will happily mate you with one.
那他妈什么...
What does that--
这他妈电线挡道了
It's this cord in the fucking way.
我踩到线了 挪开点
I'm stepping on the cord. Move the cord.
把线往那边挪挪 省得我下次又滑倒!
Move the cord over there so I don't slip on it next time!
- 对不起 对不起 - 省得我折了脚踝!
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - So I don't break my ankle!
远藤! 远藤!
Endo! Endo!
- 你会说英语吗? - 会
- You speak English? - Yeah.
他在说什么?
What's he saying?
"我们欢迎一位特别嘉宾"
"We are welcoming a special guest."
"拉姆·赛斯先生 请上台"
"Mr. Ram Sethi. Come on up."
谢谢
Thank you.
也谢谢洛克威尔先生 举办了这么一场令人难忘的活动
And thank you, Mr. Rockwell, for hosting such an unforgettable event.
咱们刚才看到的 只是下周精彩内容的一个预告
What we have just witnessed is a mere taste of what is to come next week
届时世界顶尖选手们将同台竞技
when the finest players in the world will be competing
挑战你们家乡的英雄 远藤琴音先生
against your hometown hero, Koto Endo-san.
废话不多说 请出小猪阿古
No more words from me. Let's bring on Agu the pig
看看这位美国人怎么亲它吧
and see the American plant a kiss on him.
"现在把猪请上台"
"Now we bring the pig onto the stage."
等等 等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
亲猪之前 我想先跟他真刀真枪赛一场
I want to play him in a real game first before I kiss the pig.
我想跟他真正较量一下
I want to play him in a real game.
告诉他 我想来场不掺水的比赛
Tell him I want to play him in a game that's not a sham.
告诉他!
Tell him!
你 告诉观众 刚才那是假赛
You, tell the audience that was a fake game.
告诉他们刚才是在演戏 我想跟他来场认真的
Tell them it was a sham and I want to play a real game against him.
- 我办不到 - 为什么办不到?
- I cannot do that for you. - Why can't you do that?
刚才那是假赛 是排演好的
That was a fake game. That was staged.
没一点是真的
No part of that was real.
我根本没发挥实力
I was not playing to the best of my ability.
这是对在场所有人的极大不尊重
It was an enormous form of disrespect to everyone here.
嘿 听着 谁想看真比赛?
Hey, listen, who wants a real game?
举手示意下 快点
Show of hands. Come on.
等等 这位先生 这位先生
Wait, this man. This man.
马蒂 你说得对 咱们想看真比赛!
Marty, you're right. We want to see the real game!
没错!
Yes!
远藤 你要站在他们那边?
En-do, you're gonna side with them?
翻译 翻译这句
Translate. Translate this.
他真要站他们那边?
He's gonna side with them, really?
任由一家美国公司把他当吉祥物 压榨他的价值卖产品?
An American company selling their product off of his back like he's a mascot?
你不是吉祥物
You're not a mascot.
布莱恩 把他带下去
Brian, get him down.
咱们来场真的 观众想看真比赛
Let's give them a real game. They want a real game.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
谢谢 谢谢 咱们得继续流程
Thank you, thank you. We need to move it along.
下周锦标赛我参加不了了
I'm not gonna be at the championship next week
全拜这混蛋所赐 我打不了锦标赛
'cause of this asshole. I'm not gonna be at the championship.
给我个机会 你羞辱了我
Give me a chance. You humiliated me.
求你了 求你了 远藤 求你
Please, please, Endo. Please.
- 拜托了 就当帮我 行吗? - 好吧
- Please, for me. Yes? - Okay.
- 太好了 行 - 成了? 他答应了?
- Yes. Okay. - Good? He says yes?
他答应了
He says yes.
谢谢 远藤 谢谢
Thank you, Endo. Thank you.
他答应了 耶
He said yes. Yes.
这小畜生
This little fuck.
开干吧
Let's do this.
操
Fuck.
好了 马蒂 行吧
Okay, Marty. All right.
耶!
Yeah!
耶 马蒂! 上啊 小伙子!
Yeah, Marty! Go boy!
省省唾沫吧 我知道我拿不到钱
You can save your breath. I know I'm not getting paid.
赢也好输也好 你一分钱都拿不到 我倒想看看你怎么回家
Win or lose, you get nothing. I wonder how you're gonna get home.
- 你别想上我的飞机 - 没关系 好吗?
- You're not getting on my plane. - It doesn't matter, okay?
除非你打算取消活动 否则咱们没什么好谈的
Unless you're planning on shutting down the event, we got nothing to discuss.
- 你觉得就这么简单? - 对 我就这么觉得
- You think it's that simple? - Yeah, I do.
让我来给你解释一下
Let me explain to you.
我生于1601年 我是个吸血鬼 我活了很久很久了
I was born in 1601. I'm a vampire. I've been around forever.
几个世纪以来 我见过很多像马蒂·毛瑟这样的人
I've met many Marty Mausers over the centuries.
有些跟我作对 有些不走正道 他们不诚实
Some of them crossed me, some weren't straight. They weren't honest.
而正是这类人 才能一直活到现在
And those are the ones that are still here.
你去赢下那场比赛 你也会永远留在这里
You go out and win that game, you're gonna be here forever too.
而且你永远不会快乐 你永远不会快乐的
And you'll never be happy. You will never be happy.
好吧 洛克威尔先生
Okay, Mr. Rockwell.
远藤! 远藤! 远藤!
Endo! Endo! Endo!
开始了!
There we go!
你他妈开玩笑呢吧
You gotta fucking kidding me.
赛点
Match point.
- 别让他逮到你 马蒂! - 耶 马蒂! 上啊 小伙子!
- Don't let him getcha, Marty! - Yeah, Marty! Go boy!
好了
Okay.
谢谢 精彩的比赛 精彩的比赛
Thank you. Good game. Good game.
你是个伟大的选手
You're a great player.
祝你在锦标赛好运 行吗? 希望你能赢
Good luck at the championship, okay? I hope you win.
贝尔维尤医院 有什么可以帮您?
Bellevue Hospital. May I help you?
嗨 是的
Hi, yes.
我想找瑞秋·米兹勒接个电话 谢谢?
I was hoping to be connected with Rachel Mizler, please?
您知道她在几楼吗?
Do you know what floor she's on?
额 她应该刚做完手术
Well, she would have gotten out of surgery.
就是你们安置这类人的地方
So wherever you keep people like that.
好的
Okay.
目前看来 她昨晚被转到了产科病房
So it looks like she was moved to the maternity ward last night.
- 产科病房? - 是的
- The maternity ward?- Yes.
- “产科病房”是什么意思? - 抱歉 我不清楚细节
- What do you mean, "the maternity ward"?- I'm sorry, I don't know the details.
她还好吗? 孩子生了吗? 离预产期还有四周呢
Is she okay? Did she have the baby? She's not due for four weeks.
我只有这些信息 她是被急救送进来的...
This is all the information that I have, that she was rushed--
“急救”? 你说什么“急救”? 你刚才还说“转到”
"Rushed"? What are you saying, "rushed"? First you said, "moved,"
- 现在又说“急救”? - 先生 请您冷静点好吗?
- now you're saying, "rushed"?- Sir, can you please calm down?
直接帮我转产科病房 谢谢
Just put me through to the maternity ward, please.
- 爸爸! - 嘿!
- Daddy! - Hey!
打扰下 产科病房是在这儿吗?
Excuse me. Maternity ward's here?
- 是的 顺着走廊走 - 谢谢
- Yes, down the hall. - Thank you.
- 先生 您得登记一下 - 不 不 我是父亲
- Sir, you need to sign in. - No, no. I'm the father.
嗨
Hi.
没事了 睡吧 我在呢 我在这儿 没事的
It's okay, sleep. I'm here. I'm here. It's okay.
我就在这里 别担心 我哪儿也不去
I'm right here. Don't worry, I'm not going anywhere.
睡吧
Go back to sleep.
我爱你
I love you.
五号床 谢谢 米兹勒
Five, please, Mizler.
你想让我抱抱他吗?
Do you want me to pick him up?
跟爸爸打个招呼
Say hi to Daddy.
是的 他在这儿呢 喊爸爸
Yeah, there he is. Say hi.
嗯 对
Yes. Yeah.